<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<srcset setid="iwslt2015-tst2014" srclang="english">
<doc docid="1741" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/meg_jay_why_30_is_not_the_new_20.html</url>
<description>Clinical psychologist Meg Jay has a bold message for twentysomethings: Contrary to popular belief, your 20s are not a throwaway decade. In this provocative talk, Jay says that just because marriage, work and kids are happening later in life, doesn't mean you can't start planning now. She gives 3 pieces of advice for how twentysomethings can re-claim adulthood in the defining decade of their lives.</description>
<keywords>aging,culture,youth</keywords>
<talkid>1741</talkid>
<title>Meg Jay: Why 30 is not the new 20</title>
<seg id="1"> When I was in my 20s, I saw my very first psychotherapy client. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I was a Ph.D. student in clinical psychology at Berkeley. </seg>
<seg id="3"> She was a 26-year-old woman named Alex. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Now Alex walked into her first session wearing jeans and a big slouchy top, and she dropped onto the couch in my office and kicked off her flats and told me she was there to talk about guy problems. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Now when I heard this, I was so relieved. </seg>
<seg id="6"> My classmate got an arsonist for her first client. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And I got a twentysomething who wanted to talk about boys. </seg>
<seg id="8"> This I thought I could handle. </seg>
<seg id="9"> But I didn't handle it. </seg>
<seg id="10"> With the funny stories that Alex would bring to session, it was easy for me just to nod my head while we kicked the can down the road. </seg>
<seg id="11"> "Thirty's the new 20," Alex would say, and as far as I could tell, she was right. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Work happened later, marriage happened later, kids happened later, even death happened later. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Twentysomethings like Alex and I had nothing but time. </seg>
<seg id="14"> But before long, my supervisor pushed me to push Alex about her love life. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I pushed back. </seg>
<seg id="16"> I said, "Sure, she's dating down, she's sleeping with a knucklehead, but it's not like she's going to marry the guy." </seg>
<seg id="17"> And then my supervisor said, "Not yet, but she might marry the next one. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Besides, the best time to work on Alex's marriage is before she has one." </seg>
<seg id="19"> That's what psychologists call an "Aha!" moment. </seg>
<seg id="20"> That was the moment I realized, 30 is not the new 20. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Yes, people settle down later than they used to, but that didn't make Alex's 20s a developmental downtime. </seg>
<seg id="22"> That made Alex's 20s a developmental sweet spot, and we were sitting there blowing it. </seg>
<seg id="23"> That was when I realized that this sort of benign neglect was a real problem, and it had real consequences, not just for Alex and her love life but for the careers and the families and the futures of twentysomethings everywhere. </seg>
<seg id="24"> There are 50 million twentysomethings in the United States right now. </seg>
<seg id="25"> We're talking about 15 percent of the population, or 100 percent if you consider that no one's getting through adulthood without going through their 20s first. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Raise your hand if you're in your 20s. </seg>
<seg id="27"> I really want to see some twentysomethings here. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Oh, yay! Y'all's awesome. </seg>
<seg id="29"> If you work with twentysomethings, you love a twentysomething, you're losing sleep over twentysomethings, I want to see — Okay. Awesome, twentysomethings really matter. </seg>
<seg id="30"> So I specialize in twentysomethings because I believe that every single one of those 50 million twentysomethings deserves to know what psychologists, sociologists, neurologists and fertility specialists already know: that claiming your 20s is one of the simplest, yet most transformative, things you can do for work, for love, for your happiness, maybe even for the world. </seg>
<seg id="31"> This is not my opinion. These are the facts. </seg>
<seg id="32"> We know that 80 percent of life's most defining moments take place by age 35. </seg>
<seg id="33"> That means that eight out of 10 of the decisions and experiences and "Aha!" moments that make your life what it is will have happened by your mid-30s. </seg>
<seg id="34"> People who are over 40, don't panic. </seg>
<seg id="35"> This crowd is going to be fine, I think. </seg>
<seg id="36"> We know that the first 10 years of a career has an exponential impact on how much money you're going to earn. </seg>
<seg id="37"> We know that more than half of Americans are married or are living with or dating their future partner by 30. </seg>
<seg id="38"> We know that the brain caps off its second and last growth spurt in your 20s as it rewires itself for adulthood, which means that whatever it is you want to change about yourself, now is the time to change it. </seg>
<seg id="39"> We know that personality changes more during your 20s than at any other time in life, and we know that female fertility peaks at age 28, and things get tricky after age 35. </seg>
<seg id="40"> So your 20s are the time to educate yourself about your body and your options. </seg>
<seg id="41"> So when we think about child development, we all know that the first five years are a critical period for language and attachment in the brain. </seg>
<seg id="42"> It's a time when your ordinary, day-to-day life has an inordinate impact on who you will become. </seg>
<seg id="43"> But what we hear less about is that there's such a thing as adult development, and our 20s are that critical period of adult development. </seg>
<seg id="44"> But this isn't what twentysomethings are hearing. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Newspapers talk about the changing timetable of adulthood. </seg>
<seg id="46"> Researchers call the 20s an extended adolescence. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Journalists coin silly nicknames for twentysomethings like "twixters" and "kidults." </seg>
<seg id="48"> It's true. </seg>
<seg id="49"> As a culture, we have trivialized what is actually the defining decade of adulthood. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Leonard Bernstein said that to achieve great things, you need a plan and not quite enough time. </seg>
<seg id="51"> Isn't that true? </seg>
<seg id="52"> So what do you think happens when you pat a twentysomething on the head and you say, "You have 10 extra years to start your life"? </seg>
<seg id="53"> Nothing happens. </seg>
<seg id="54"> You have robbed that person of his urgency and ambition, and absolutely nothing happens. </seg>
<seg id="55"> And then every day, smart, interesting twentysomethings like you or like your sons and daughters come into my office and say things like this: "I know my boyfriend's no good for me, but this relationship doesn't count. I'm just killing time." </seg>
<seg id="56"> Or they say, "Everybody says as long as I get started on a career by the time I'm 30, I'll be fine." </seg>
<seg id="57"> But then it starts to sound like this: "My 20s are almost over, and I have nothing to show for myself. </seg>
<seg id="58"> I had a better résumé the day after I graduated from college." </seg>
<seg id="59"> And then it starts to sound like this: "Dating in my 20s was like musical chairs. </seg>
<seg id="60"> Everybody was running around and having fun, but then sometime around 30 it was like the music turned off and everybody started sitting down. </seg>
<seg id="61"> I didn't want to be the only one left standing up, so sometimes I think I married my husband because he was the closest chair to me at 30." </seg>
<seg id="62"> Where are the twentysomethings here? </seg>
<seg id="63"> Do not do that. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Okay, now that sounds a little flip, but make no mistake, the stakes are very high. </seg>
<seg id="65"> When a lot has been pushed to your 30s, there is enormous thirtysomething pressure to jump-start a career, pick a city, partner up, and have two or three kids in a much shorter period of time. </seg>
<seg id="66"> Many of these things are incompatible, and as research is just starting to show, simply harder and more stressful to do all at once in our 30s. </seg>
<seg id="67"> The post-millennial midlife crisis isn't buying a red sports car. </seg>
<seg id="68"> It's realizing you can't have that career you now want. </seg>
<seg id="69"> It's realizing you can't have that child you now want, or you can't give your child a sibling. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Too many thirtysomethings and fortysomethings look at themselves, and at me, sitting across the room, and say about their 20s, "What was I doing? What was I thinking?" </seg>
<seg id="71"> I want to change what twentysomethings are doing and thinking. </seg>
<seg id="72"> Here's a story about how that can go. </seg>
<seg id="73"> It's a story about a woman named Emma. </seg>
<seg id="74"> At 25, Emma came to my office because she was, in her words, having an identity crisis. </seg>
<seg id="75"> She said she thought she might like to work in art or entertainment, but she hadn't decided yet, so she'd spent the last few years waiting tables instead. </seg>
<seg id="76"> Because it was cheaper, she lived with a boyfriend who displayed his temper more than his ambition. </seg>
<seg id="77"> And as hard as her 20s were, her early life had been even harder. </seg>
<seg id="78"> She often cried in our sessions, but then would collect herself by saying, "You can't pick your family, but you can pick your friends." </seg>
<seg id="79"> Well one day, Emma comes in and she hangs her head in her lap, and she sobbed for most of the hour. </seg>
<seg id="80"> She'd just bought a new address book, and she'd spent the morning filling in her many contacts, but then she'd been left staring at that empty blank that comes after the words "In case of emergency, please call ... ." </seg>
<seg id="81"> She was nearly hysterical when she looked at me and said, "Who's going to be there for me if I get in a car wreck? </seg>
<seg id="82"> Who's going to take care of me if I have cancer?" </seg>
<seg id="83"> Now in that moment, it took everything I had not to say, "I will." </seg>
<seg id="84"> But what Emma needed wasn't some therapist who really, really cared. </seg>
<seg id="85"> Emma needed a better life, and I knew this was her chance. </seg>
<seg id="86"> I had learned too much since I first worked with Alex to just sit there while Emma's defining decade went parading by. </seg>
<seg id="87"> So over the next weeks and months, I told Emma three things that every twentysomething, male or female, deserves to hear. </seg>
<seg id="88"> First, I told Emma to forget about having an identity crisis and get some identity capital. </seg>
<seg id="89"> By get identity capital, I mean do something that adds value to who you are. </seg>
<seg id="90"> Do something that's an investment in who you might want to be next. </seg>
<seg id="91"> I didn't know the future of Emma's career, and no one knows the future of work, but I do know this: Identity capital begets identity capital. </seg>
<seg id="92"> So now is the time for that cross-country job, that internship, that startup you want to try. </seg>
<seg id="93"> I'm not discounting twentysomething exploration here, but I am discounting exploration that's not supposed to count, which, by the way, is not exploration. </seg>
<seg id="94"> That's procrastination. </seg>
<seg id="95"> I told Emma to explore work and make it count. </seg>
<seg id="96"> Second, I told Emma that the urban tribe is overrated. </seg>
<seg id="97"> Best friends are great for giving rides to the airport, but twentysomethings who huddle together with like-minded peers limit who they know, what they know, how they think, how they speak, and where they work. </seg>
<seg id="98"> That new piece of capital, that new person to date almost always comes from outside the inner circle. </seg>
<seg id="99"> New things come from what are called our weak ties, our friends of friends of friends. </seg>
<seg id="100"> So yes, half of twentysomethings are un- or under-employed. </seg>
<seg id="101"> But half aren't, and weak ties are how you get yourself into that group. </seg>
<seg id="102"> Half of new jobs are never posted, so reaching out to your neighbor's boss is how you get that un-posted job. </seg>
<seg id="103"> It's not cheating. It's the science of how information spreads. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Last but not least, Emma believed that you can't pick your family, but you can pick your friends. </seg>
<seg id="105"> Now this was true for her growing up, but as a twentysomething, soon Emma would pick her family when she partnered with someone and created a family of her own. </seg>
<seg id="106"> I told Emma the time to start picking your family is now. </seg>
<seg id="107"> Now you may be thinking that 30 is actually a better time to settle down than 20, or even 25, and I agree with you. </seg>
<seg id="108"> But grabbing whoever you're living with or sleeping with when everyone on Facebook starts walking down the aisle is not progress. </seg>
<seg id="109"> The best time to work on your marriage is before you have one, and that means being as intentional with love as you are with work. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Picking your family is about consciously choosing who and what you want rather than just making it work or killing time with whoever happens to be choosing you. </seg>
<seg id="111"> So what happened to Emma? </seg>
<seg id="112"> Well, we went through that address book, and she found an old roommate's cousin who worked at an art museum in another state. </seg>
<seg id="113"> That weak tie helped her get a job there. </seg>
<seg id="114"> That job offer gave her the reason to leave that live-in boyfriend. </seg>
<seg id="115"> Now, five years later, she's a special events planner for museums. </seg>
<seg id="116"> She's married to a man she mindfully chose. </seg>
<seg id="117"> She loves her new career, she loves her new family, and she sent me a card that said, "Now the emergency contact blanks don't seem big enough." </seg>
<seg id="118"> Now Emma's story made that sound easy, but that's what I love about working with twentysomethings. </seg>
<seg id="119"> They are so easy to help. </seg>
<seg id="120"> Twentysomethings are like airplanes just leaving LAX, bound for somewhere west. </seg>
<seg id="121"> Right after takeoff, a slight change in course is the difference between landing in Alaska or Fiji. </seg>
<seg id="122"> Likewise, at 21 or 25 or even 29, one good conversation, one good break, one good TED Talk, can have an enormous effect across years and even generations to come. </seg>
<seg id="123"> So here's an idea worth spreading to every twentysomething you know. </seg>
<seg id="124"> It's as simple as what I learned to say to Alex. </seg>
<seg id="125"> It's what I now have the privilege of saying to twentysomethings like Emma every single day: Thirty is not the new 20, so claim your adulthood, get some identity capital, use your weak ties, pick your family. </seg>
<seg id="126"> Don't be defined by what you didn't know or didn't do. </seg>
<seg id="127"> You're deciding your life right now. </seg>
<seg id="128"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1781" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/jinha_lee_a_tool_that_lets_you_touch_pixels.html</url>
<description>The border between our physical world and the digital information surrounding us has been getting thinner and thinner. Designer and engineer Jinha Lee wants to dissolve it altogether. As he demonstrates in this short, gasp-inducing talk, his ideas include a pen that penetrates into a screen to draw 3D models and SpaceTop, a computer desktop prototype that lets you reach through the screen to manipulate digital objects.</description>
<keywords>TED Fellows,computers,design,interface design,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1781</talkid>
<title>Jinha Lee: Reach into the computer and grab a pixel</title>
<seg id="1"> Throughout the history of computers we've been striving to shorten the gap between us and digital information, the gap between our physical world and the world in the screen where our imagination can go wild. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And this gap has become shorter, shorter, and even shorter, and now this gap is shortened down to less than a millimeter, the thickness of a touch-screen glass, and the power of computing has become accessible to everyone. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But I wondered, what if there could be no boundary at all? </seg>
<seg id="4"> I started to imagine what this would look like. </seg>
<seg id="5"> First, I created this tool which penetrates into the digital space, so when you press it hard on the screen, it transfers its physical body into pixels. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Designers can materialize their ideas directly in 3D, and surgeons can practice on virtual organs underneath the screen. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So with this tool, this boundary has been broken. </seg>
<seg id="8"> But our two hands still remain outside the screen. </seg>
<seg id="9"> How can you reach inside and interact with the digital information using the full dexterity of our hands? </seg>
<seg id="10"> At Microsoft Applied Sciences, along with my mentor Cati Boulanger, I redesigned the computer and turned a little space above the keyboard into a digital workspace. </seg>
<seg id="11"> By combining a transparent display and depth cameras for sensing your fingers and face, now you can lift up your hands from the keyboard and reach inside this 3D space and grab pixels with your bare hands. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Because windows and files have a position in the real space, selecting them is as easy as grabbing a book off your shelf. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Then you can flip through this book while highlighting the lines, words on the virtual touch pad below each floating window. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Architects can stretch or rotate the models with their two hands directly. </seg>
<seg id="15"> So in these examples, we are reaching into the digital world. </seg>
<seg id="16"> But how about reversing its role and having the digital information reach us instead? </seg>
<seg id="17"> I'm sure many of us have had the experience of buying and returning items online. </seg>
<seg id="18"> But now you don't have to worry about it. </seg>
<seg id="19"> What I got here is an online augmented fitting room. </seg>
<seg id="20"> This is a view that you get from head-mounted or see-through display when the system understands the geometry of your body. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Taking this idea further, I started to think, instead of just seeing these pixels in our space, how can we make it physical so that we can touch and feel it? </seg>
<seg id="22"> What would such a future look like? </seg>
<seg id="23"> At MIT Media Lab, along with my advisor Hiroshi Ishii and my collaborator Rehmi Post, we created this one physical pixel. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Well, in this case, this spherical magnet acts like a 3D pixel in our space, which means that both computers and people can move this object to anywhere within this little 3D space. </seg>
<seg id="25"> What we did was essentially canceling gravity and controlling the movement by combining magnetic levitation and mechanical actuation and sensing technologies. </seg>
<seg id="26"> And by digitally programming the object, we are liberating the object from constraints of time and space, which means that now, human motions can be recorded and played back and left permanently in the physical world. </seg>
<seg id="27"> So choreography can be taught physically over distance and Michael Jordan's famous shooting can be replicated over and over as a physical reality. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Students can use this as a tool to learn about the complex concepts such as planetary motion, physics, and unlike computer screens or textbooks, this is a real, tangible experience that you can touch and feel, and it's very powerful. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And what's more exciting than just turning what's currently in the computer physical is to start imagining how programming the world will alter even our daily physical activities. </seg>
<seg id="30"> As you can see, the digital information will not just show us something but it will start directly acting upon us as a part of our physical surroundings without disconnecting ourselves from our world. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Today, we started by talking about the boundary, but if we remove this boundary, the only boundary left is our imagination. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1755" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/lisa_bu_how_books_can_open_your_mind.html</url>
<description>What happens when a dream you've held since childhood … doesn't come true? As Lisa Bu adjusted to a new life in the United States, she turned to books to expand her mind and create a new path for herself. She shares her unique approach to reading in this lovely, personal talk about the magic of books.</description>
<keywords>creativity,culture,entertainment,literature</keywords>
<talkid>1755</talkid>
<title>Lisa Bu: How books can open your mind</title>
<seg id="1"> So I was trained to become a gymnast for two years in Hunan, China in the 1970s. </seg>
<seg id="2"> When I was in the first grade, the government wanted to transfer me to a school for athletes, all expenses paid. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But my tiger mother said, "No." </seg>
<seg id="4"> My parents wanted me to become an engineer like them. </seg>
<seg id="5"> After surviving the Cultural Revolution, they firmly believed there's only one sure way to happiness: a safe and well-paid job. </seg>
<seg id="6"> It is not important if I like the job or not. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But my dream was to become a Chinese opera singer. </seg>
<seg id="8"> That is me playing my imaginary piano. </seg>
<seg id="9"> An opera singer must start training young to learn acrobatics, so I tried everything I could to go to opera school. </seg>
<seg id="10"> I even wrote to the school principal and the host of a radio show. </seg>
<seg id="11"> But no adults liked the idea. </seg>
<seg id="12"> No adults believed I was serious. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Only my friends supported me, but they were kids, just as powerless as I was. </seg>
<seg id="14"> So at age 15, I knew I was too old to be trained. </seg>
<seg id="15"> My dream would never come true. </seg>
<seg id="16"> I was afraid that for the rest of my life some second-class happiness would be the best I could hope for. </seg>
<seg id="17"> But that's so unfair. </seg>
<seg id="18"> So I was determined to find another calling. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Nobody around to teach me? Fine. </seg>
<seg id="20"> I turned to books. </seg>
<seg id="21"> I satisfied my hunger for parental advice from this book by a family of writers and musicians.["Correspondence in the Family of Fou Lei"] I found my role model of an independent woman when Confucian tradition requires obedience.["Jane Eyre"] And I learned to be efficient from this book.["Cheaper by the Dozen"] And I was inspired to study abroad after reading these. </seg>
<seg id="22"> ["Complete Works of Sanmao" ] ["Lessons From History" by Nan Huaijin] I came to the U.S. in 1995, so which books did I read here first? </seg>
<seg id="23"> Books banned in China, of course. </seg>
<seg id="24"> "The Good Earth" is about Chinese peasant life. </seg>
<seg id="25"> That's just not convenient for propaganda. Got it. </seg>
<seg id="26"> The Bible is interesting, but strange. </seg>
<seg id="27"> That's a topic for a different day. </seg>
<seg id="28"> But the fifth commandment gave me an epiphany: "You shall honor your father and mother." </seg>
<seg id="29"> "Honor," I said. "That's so different, and better, than obey." </seg>
<seg id="30"> So it becomes my tool to climb out of this Confucian guilt trap and to restart my relationship with my parents. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Encountering a new culture also started my habit of comparative reading. </seg>
<seg id="32"> It offers many insights. </seg>
<seg id="33"> For example, I found this map out of place at first because this is what Chinese students grew up with. </seg>
<seg id="34"> It had never occurred to me, China doesn't have to be at the center of the world. </seg>
<seg id="35"> A map actually carries somebody's view. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Comparative reading actually is nothing new. </seg>
<seg id="37"> It's a standard practice in the academic world. </seg>
<seg id="38"> There are even research fields such as comparative religion and comparative literature. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Compare and contrast gives scholars a more complete understanding of a topic. </seg>
<seg id="40"> So I thought, well, if comparative reading works for research, why not do it in daily life too? </seg>
<seg id="41"> So I started reading books in pairs. </seg>
<seg id="42"> So they can be about people -- ["Benjamin Franklin" by Walter Isaacson]["John Adams" by David McCullough] -- who are involved in the same event, or friends with shared experiences. </seg>
<seg id="43"> ["Personal History" by Katharine Graham]["The Snowball: Warren Buffett and the Business of Life," by Alice Schroeder] I also compare the same stories in different genres -- [Holy Bible: King James Version]["Lamb" by Chrisopher Moore] -- or similar stories from different cultures, as Joseph Campbell did in his wonderful book.["The Power of Myth" by Joseph Campbell] For example, both the Christ and the Buddha went through three temptations. </seg>
<seg id="44"> For the Christ, the temptations are economic, political and spiritual. </seg>
<seg id="45"> For the Buddha, they are all psychological: lust, fear and social duty -- interesting. </seg>
<seg id="46"> So if you know a foreign language, it's also fun to read your favorite books in two languages. </seg>
<seg id="47"> ["The Way of Chuang Tzu" Thomas Merton]["Tao: The Watercourse Way" Alan Watts] Instead of lost in translation, I found there is much to gain. </seg>
<seg id="48"> For example, it's through translation that I realized "happiness" in Chinese literally means "fast joy." Huh! </seg>
<seg id="49"> "Bride" in Chinese literally means "new mother." Uh-oh. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Books have given me a magic portal to connect with people of the past and the present. </seg>
<seg id="51"> I know I shall never feel lonely or powerless again. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Having a dream shattered really is nothing compared to what many others have suffered. </seg>
<seg id="53"> I have come to believe that coming true is not the only purpose of a dream. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Its most important purpose is to get us in touch with where dreams come from, where passion comes from, where happiness comes from. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Even a shattered dream can do that for you. </seg>
<seg id="56"> So because of books, I'm here today, happy, living again with a purpose and a clarity, most of the time. </seg>
<seg id="57"> So may books be always with you. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="60"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1852" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/parul_sehgal_an_ode_to_envy.html</url>
<description>What is jealousy? What drives it, and why do we secretly love it? No study has ever been able to capture its "loneliness, longevity, grim thrill" -- that is, says Parul Sehgal, except for fiction. In an eloquent meditation she scours pages from literature to show how jealousy is not so different from a quest for knowledge.</description>
<keywords>book,culture,literature,love,relationships,sex,writing</keywords>
<talkid>1852</talkid>
<title>Parul Sehgal: An ode to envy</title>
<seg id="1"> So when I was eight years old, a new girl came to join the class, and she was so impressive, as the new girl always seems to be. </seg>
<seg id="2"> She had vast quantities of very shiny hair and a cute little pencil case, super strong on state capitals, just a great speller. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And I just curdled with jealousy that year, until I hatched my devious plan. </seg>
<seg id="4"> So one day I stayed a little late after school, a little too late, and I lurked in the girls' bathroom. </seg>
<seg id="5"> When the coast was clear, I emerged, crept into the classroom, and took from my teacher's desk the grade book. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And then I did it. </seg>
<seg id="7"> I fiddled with my rival's grades, just a little, just demoted some of those A's. </seg>
<seg id="8"> All of those A's. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And I got ready to return the book to the drawer, when hang on, some of my other classmates had appallingly good grades too. </seg>
<seg id="10"> So, in a frenzy, I corrected everybody's marks, not imaginatively. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I gave everybody a row of D's and I gave myself a row of A's, just because I was there, you know, might as well. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And I am still baffled by my behavior. </seg>
<seg id="13"> I don't understand where the idea came from. </seg>
<seg id="14"> I don't understand why I felt so great doing it. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I felt great. </seg>
<seg id="16"> I don't understand why I was never caught. </seg>
<seg id="17"> I mean, it should have been so blatantly obvious. </seg>
<seg id="18"> I was never caught. </seg>
<seg id="19"> But most of all, I am baffled by, why did it bother me so much that this little girl, this tiny little girl, was so good at spelling? </seg>
<seg id="20"> Jealousy baffles me. </seg>
<seg id="21"> It's so mysterious, and it's so pervasive. </seg>
<seg id="22"> We know babies suffer from jealousy. </seg>
<seg id="23"> We know primates do. Bluebirds are actually very prone. </seg>
<seg id="24"> We know that jealousy is the number one cause of spousal murder in the United States. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And yet, I have never read a study that can parse to me its loneliness or its longevity or its grim thrill. </seg>
<seg id="26"> For that, we have to go to fiction, because the novel is the lab that has studied jealousy in every possible configuration. </seg>
<seg id="27"> In fact, I don't know if it's an exaggeration to say that if we didn't have jealousy, would we even have literature? </seg>
<seg id="28"> Well no faithless Helen, no "Odyssey." </seg>
<seg id="29"> No jealous king, no "Arabian Nights." </seg>
<seg id="30"> No Shakespeare. </seg>
<seg id="31"> There goes high school reading lists, because we're losing "Sound and the Fury," we're losing "Gatsby," "Sun Also Rises," we're losing "Madame Bovary," "Anna K." </seg>
<seg id="32"> No jealousy, no Proust. And now, I mean, I know it's fashionable to say that Proust has the answers to everything, but in the case of jealousy, he kind of does. </seg>
<seg id="33"> This year is the centennial of his masterpiece, "In Search of Lost Time," and it's the most exhaustive study of sexual jealousy and just regular competitiveness, my brand, that we can hope to have. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And we think about Proust, we think about the sentimental bits, right? </seg>
<seg id="35"> We think about a little boy trying to get to sleep. </seg>
<seg id="36"> We think about a madeleine moistened in lavender tea. </seg>
<seg id="37"> We forget how harsh his vision was. </seg>
<seg id="38"> We forget how pitiless he is. </seg>
<seg id="39"> I mean, these are books that Virginia Woolf said were tough as cat gut. </seg>
<seg id="40"> I don't know what cat gut is, but let's assume it's formidable. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Let's look at why they go so well together, the novel and jealousy, jealousy and Proust. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Is it something as obvious as that jealousy, which boils down into person, desire, impediment, is such a solid narrative foundation? </seg>
<seg id="43"> I don't know. I think it cuts very close to the bone, because let's think about what happens when we feel jealous. </seg>
<seg id="44"> When we feel jealous, we tell ourselves a story. </seg>
<seg id="45"> We tell ourselves a story about other people's lives, and these stories make us feel terrible because they're designed to make us feel terrible. </seg>
<seg id="46"> As the teller of the tale and the audience, we know just what details to include, to dig that knife in. Right? </seg>
<seg id="47"> Jealousy makes us all amateur novelists, and this is something Proust understood. </seg>
<seg id="48"> In the first volume, Swann's Way, the series of books, Swann, one of the main characters, is thinking very fondly of his mistress and how great she is in bed, and suddenly, in the course of a few sentences, and these are Proustian sentences, so they're long as rivers, but in the course of a few sentences, he suddenly recoils and he realizes, "Hang on, everything I love about this woman, somebody else would love about this woman. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Everything that she does that gives me pleasure could be giving somebody else pleasure, maybe right about now." </seg>
<seg id="50"> And this is the story he starts to tell himself, and from then on, Proust writes that every fresh charm Swann detects in his mistress, he adds to his "collection of instruments in his private torture chamber." </seg>
<seg id="51"> Now Swann and Proust, we have to admit, were notoriously jealous. </seg>
<seg id="52"> You know, Proust's boyfriends would have to leave the country if they wanted to break up with him. </seg>
<seg id="53"> But you don't have to be that jealous to concede that it's hard work. Right? </seg>
<seg id="54"> Jealousy is exhausting. </seg>
<seg id="55"> It's a hungry emotion. It must be fed. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And what does jealousy like? </seg>
<seg id="57"> Jealousy likes information. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Jealousy likes details. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Jealousy likes the vast quantities of shiny hair, the cute little pencil case. </seg>
<seg id="60"> Jealousy likes photos. </seg>
<seg id="61"> That's why Instagram is such a hit. </seg>
<seg id="62"> Proust actually links the language of scholarship and jealousy. </seg>
<seg id="63"> When Swann is in his jealous throes, and suddenly he's listening at doorways and bribing his mistress' servants, he defends these behaviors. </seg>
<seg id="64"> He says, "You know, look, I know you think this is repugnant, but it is no different from interpreting an ancient text or looking at a monument." </seg>
<seg id="65"> He says, "They are scientific investigations with real intellectual value." </seg>
<seg id="66"> Proust is trying to show us that jealousy feels intolerable and makes us look absurd, but it is, at its crux, a quest for knowledge, a quest for truth, painful truth, and actually, where Proust is concerned, the more painful the truth, the better. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Grief, humiliation, loss: These were the avenues to wisdom for Proust. </seg>
<seg id="68"> He says, "A woman whom we need, who makes us suffer, elicits from us a gamut of feelings far more profound and vital than a man of genius who interests us." </seg>
<seg id="69"> Is he telling us to just go and find cruel women? </seg>
<seg id="70"> No. I think he's trying to say that jealousy reveals us to ourselves. </seg>
<seg id="71"> And does any other emotion crack us open in this particular way? </seg>
<seg id="72"> Does any other emotion reveal to us our aggression and our hideous ambition and our entitlement? </seg>
<seg id="73"> Does any other emotion teach us to look with such peculiar intensity? </seg>
<seg id="74"> Freud would write about this later. </seg>
<seg id="75"> One day, Freud was visited by this very anxious young man who was consumed with the thought of his wife cheating on him. </seg>
<seg id="76"> And Freud says, it's something strange about this guy, because he's not looking at what his wife is doing. </seg>
<seg id="77"> Because she's blameless; everybody knows it. </seg>
<seg id="78"> The poor creature is just under suspicion for no cause. </seg>
<seg id="79"> But he's looking for things that his wife is doing without noticing, unintentional behaviors. </seg>
<seg id="80"> Is she smiling too brightly here, or did she accidentally brush up against a man there? </seg>
<seg id="81"> [Freud] says that the man is becoming the custodian of his wife's unconscious. </seg>
<seg id="82"> The novel is very good on this point. </seg>
<seg id="83"> The novel is very good at describing how jealousy trains us to look with intensity but not accuracy. </seg>
<seg id="84"> In fact, the more intensely jealous we are, the more we become residents of fantasy. </seg>
<seg id="85"> And this is why, I think, jealousy doesn't just provoke us to do violent things or illegal things. </seg>
<seg id="86"> Jealousy prompts us to behave in ways that are wildly inventive. </seg>
<seg id="87"> Now I'm thinking of myself at eight, I concede, but I'm also thinking of this story I heard on the news. </seg>
<seg id="88"> A 52-year-old Michigan woman was caught creating a fake Facebook account from which she sent vile, hideous messages to herself for a year. </seg>
<seg id="89"> For a year. A year. </seg>
<seg id="90"> And she was trying to frame her ex-boyfriend's new girlfriend, and I have to confess when I heard this, I just reacted with admiration. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Because, I mean, let's be real. </seg>
<seg id="92"> What immense, if misplaced, creativity. Right? </seg>
<seg id="93"> This is something from a novel. </seg>
<seg id="94"> This is something from a Patricia Highsmith novel. </seg>
<seg id="95"> Now Highsmith is a particular favorite of mine. </seg>
<seg id="96"> She is the very brilliant and bizarre woman of American letters. </seg>
<seg id="97"> She's the author of "Strangers on a Train" and "The Talented Mr. Ripley," books that are all about how jealousy, it muddles our minds, and once we're in the sphere, in that realm of jealousy, the membrane between what is and what could be can be pierced in an instant. </seg>
<seg id="98"> Take Tom Ripley, her most famous character. </seg>
<seg id="99"> Now, Tom Ripley goes from wanting you or wanting what you have to being you and having what you once had, and you're under the floorboards, he's answering to your name, he's wearing your rings, emptying your bank account. </seg>
<seg id="100"> That's one way to go. </seg>
<seg id="101"> But what do we do? We can't go the Tom Ripley route. </seg>
<seg id="102"> I can't give the world D's, as much as I would really like to, some days. </seg>
<seg id="103"> And it's a pity, because we live in envious times. </seg>
<seg id="104"> We live in jealous times. </seg>
<seg id="105"> I mean, we're all good citizens of social media, aren't we, where the currency is envy? </seg>
<seg id="106"> Does the novel show us a way out? I'm not sure. </seg>
<seg id="107"> So let's do what characters always do when they're not sure, when they are in possession of a mystery. </seg>
<seg id="108"> Let's go to 221B Baker Street and ask for Sherlock Holmes. </seg>
<seg id="109"> When people think of Holmes, they think of his nemesis being Professor Moriarty, right, this criminal mastermind. </seg>
<seg id="110"> But I've always preferred [Inspector] Lestrade, who is the rat-faced head of Scotland Yard who needs Holmes desperately, needs Holmes' genius, but resents him. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Oh, it's so familiar to me. </seg>
<seg id="112"> So Lestrade needs his help, resents him, and sort of seethes with bitterness over the course of the mysteries. </seg>
<seg id="113"> But as they work together, something starts to change, and finally in "The Adventure of the Six Napoleons," once Holmes comes in, dazzles everybody with his solution, Lestrade turns to Holmes and he says, "We're not jealous of you, Mr. Holmes. </seg>
<seg id="114"> We're proud of you." </seg>
<seg id="115"> And he says that there's not a man at Scotland Yard who wouldn't want to shake Sherlock Holmes' hand. </seg>
<seg id="116"> It's one of the few times we see Holmes moved in the mysteries, and I find it very moving, this little scene, but it's also mysterious, right? </seg>
<seg id="117"> It seems to treat jealousy as a problem of geometry, not emotion. </seg>
<seg id="118"> You know, one minute Holmes is on the other side from Lestrade. </seg>
<seg id="119"> The next minute they're on the same side. </seg>
<seg id="120"> Suddenly, Lestrade is letting himself admire this mind that he's resented. </seg>
<seg id="121"> Could it be so simple though? </seg>
<seg id="122"> What if jealousy really is a matter of geometry, just a matter of where we allow ourselves to stand in relation to another? </seg>
<seg id="123"> Well, maybe then we wouldn't have to resent somebody's excellence. </seg>
<seg id="124"> We could align ourselves with it. </seg>
<seg id="125"> But I like contingency plans. </seg>
<seg id="126"> So while we wait for that to happen, let us remember that we have fiction for consolation. </seg>
<seg id="127"> Fiction alone demystifies jealousy. </seg>
<seg id="128"> Fiction alone domesticates it, invites it to the table. </seg>
<seg id="129"> And look who it gathers: sweet Lestrade, terrifying Tom Ripley, crazy Swann, Marcel Proust himself. </seg>
<seg id="130"> We are in excellent company. </seg>
<seg id="131"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1858" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/robin_nagle_what_i_discovered_in_new_york_city_trash.html</url>
<description>New York City residents produce 11,000 tons of garbage every day. Every day! This astonishing statistic is just one of the reasons Robin Nagle started a research project with the city's Department of Sanitation. She walked the routes, operated mechanical brooms, even drove a garbage truck herself--all so she could answer a simple-sounding but complicated question: who cleans up after us?</description>
<keywords>anthropology,business,culture</keywords>
<talkid>1858</talkid>
<title>Robin Nagle: What I discovered in New York City trash</title>
<seg id="1"> I was about 10 years old on a camping trip with my dad in the Adirondack Mountains, a wilderness area in the northern part of New York State. </seg>
<seg id="2"> It was a beautiful day. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The forest was sparkling. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The sun made the leaves glow like stained glass, and if it weren't for the path we were following, we could almost pretend we were the first human beings to ever walk that land. </seg>
<seg id="5"> We got to our campsite. </seg>
<seg id="6"> It was a lean-to on a bluff looking over a crystal, beautiful lake, when I discovered a horror. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Behind the lean-to was a dump, maybe 40 feet square with rotting apple cores and balled-up aluminum foil, and a dead sneaker. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And I was astonished, I was very angry, and I was deeply confused. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The campers who were too lazy to take out what they had brought in, who did they think would clean up after them? </seg>
<seg id="10"> That question stayed with me, and it simplified a little. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Who cleans up after us? </seg>
<seg id="12"> However you configure or wherever you place the us, who cleans up after us in Istanbul? </seg>
<seg id="13"> Who cleans up after us in Rio or in Paris or in London? </seg>
<seg id="14"> Here in New York, the Department of Sanitation cleans up after us, to the tune of 11,000 tons of garbage and 2,000 tons of recyclables every day. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I wanted to get to know them as individuals. </seg>
<seg id="16"> I wanted to understand who takes the job. </seg>
<seg id="17"> What's it like to wear the uniform and bear that burden? </seg>
<seg id="18"> So I started a research project with them. </seg>
<seg id="19"> I rode in the trucks and walked the routes and interviewed people in offices and facilities all over the city, and I learned a lot, but I was still an outsider. </seg>
<seg id="20"> I needed to go deeper. </seg>
<seg id="21"> So I took the job as a sanitation worker. </seg>
<seg id="22"> I didn't just ride in the trucks now. I drove the trucks. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And I operated the mechanical brooms and I plowed the snow. </seg>
<seg id="24"> It was a remarkable privilege and an amazing education. </seg>
<seg id="25"> Everyone asks about the smell. </seg>
<seg id="26"> It's there, but it's not as prevalent as you think, and on days when it is really bad, you get used to it rather quickly. </seg>
<seg id="27"> The weight takes a long time to get used to. </seg>
<seg id="28"> I knew people who were several years on the job whose bodies were still adjusting to the burden of bearing on your body tons of trash every week. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Then there's the danger. </seg>
<seg id="30"> According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, sanitation work is one of the 10 most dangerous occupations in the country, and I learned why. </seg>
<seg id="31"> You're in and out of traffic all day, and it's zooming around you. </seg>
<seg id="32"> It just wants to get past you, so it's often the motorist is not paying attention. </seg>
<seg id="33"> That's really bad for the worker. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And then the garbage itself is full of hazards that often fly back out of the truck and do terrible harm. </seg>
<seg id="35"> I also learned about the relentlessness of trash. </seg>
<seg id="36"> When you step off the curb and you see a city from behind a truck, you come to understand that trash is like a force of nature unto itself. </seg>
<seg id="37"> It never stops coming. </seg>
<seg id="38"> It's also like a form of respiration or circulation. </seg>
<seg id="39"> It must always be in motion. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And then there's the stigma. </seg>
<seg id="41"> You put on the uniform, and you become invisible until someone is upset with you for whatever reason like you've blocked traffic with your truck, or you're taking a break too close to their home, or you're drinking coffee in their diner, and they will come and scorn you, and tell you that they don't want you anywhere near them. </seg>
<seg id="42"> I find the stigma especially ironic, because I strongly believe that sanitation workers are the most important labor force on the streets of the city, for three reasons. </seg>
<seg id="43"> They are the first guardians of public health. </seg>
<seg id="44"> If they're not taking away trash efficiently and effectively every day, it starts to spill out of its containments, and the dangers inherent to it threaten us in very real ways. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Diseases we've had in check for decades and centuries burst forth again and start to harm us. </seg>
<seg id="46"> The economy needs them. </seg>
<seg id="47"> If we can't throw out the old stuff, we have no room for the new stuff, so then the engines of the economy start to sputter when consumption is compromised. </seg>
<seg id="48"> I'm not advocating capitalism, I'm just pointing out their relationship. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And then there's what I call our average, necessary quotidian velocity. </seg>
<seg id="50"> By that I simply mean how fast we're used to moving in the contemporary day and age. </seg>
<seg id="51"> We usually don't care for, repair, clean, carry around our coffee cup, our shopping bag, our bottle of water. </seg>
<seg id="52"> We use them, we throw them out, we forget about them, because we know there's a workforce on the other side that's going to take it all away. </seg>
<seg id="53"> So I want to suggest today a couple of ways to think about sanitation that will perhaps help ameliorate the stigma and bring them into this conversation of how to craft a city that is sustainable and humane. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Their work, I think, is kind of liturgical. </seg>
<seg id="55"> They're on the streets every day, rhythmically. </seg>
<seg id="56"> They wear a uniform in many cities. </seg>
<seg id="57"> You know when to expect them. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And their work lets us do our work. </seg>
<seg id="59"> They are almost a form of reassurance. </seg>
<seg id="60"> The flow that they maintain keeps us safe from ourselves, from our own dross, our cast-offs, and that flow must be maintained always no matter what. </seg>
<seg id="61"> On the day after September 11 in 2001, I heard the growl of a sanitation truck on the street, and I grabbed my infant son and I ran downstairs and there was a man doing his paper recycling route like he did every Wednesday. </seg>
<seg id="62"> And I tried to thank him for doing his work on that day of all days, but I started to cry. </seg>
<seg id="63"> And he looked at me, and he just nodded, and he said, "We're going to be okay. </seg>
<seg id="64"> We're going to be okay." </seg>
<seg id="65"> It was a little while later that I started my research with sanitation, and I met that man again. </seg>
<seg id="66"> His name is Paulie, and we worked together many times, and we became good friends. </seg>
<seg id="67"> I want to believe that Paulie was right. </seg>
<seg id="68"> We are going to be okay. </seg>
<seg id="69"> But in our effort to reconfigure how we as a species exist on this planet, we must include and take account of all the costs, including the very real human cost of the labor. </seg>
<seg id="70"> And we also would be well informed to reach out to the people who do that work and get their expertise on how do we think about, how do we create systems around sustainability that perhaps take us from curbside recycling, which is a remarkable success across 40 years, across the United States and countries around the world, and lift us up to a broader horizon where we're looking at other forms of waste that could be lessened from manufacturing and industrial sources. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Municipal waste, what we think of when we talk about garbage, accounts for three percent of the nation's waste stream. </seg>
<seg id="72"> It's a remarkable statistic. </seg>
<seg id="73"> So in the flow of your days, in the flow of your lives, next time you see someone whose job is to clean up after you, take a moment to acknowledge them. </seg>
<seg id="74"> Take a moment to say thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1898" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/maysoon_zayid_i_got_99_problems_palsy_is_just_one.html</url>
<description>"I have cerebral palsy. I shake all the time," Maysoon Zayid announces at the beginning of this exhilarating, hilarious talk. "I'm like Shakira meets Muhammad Ali." With grace and wit, the Arab-American comedian takes us on a whistle-stop tour of her adventures as an actress, stand-up comic, philanthropist and advocate for the disabled.</description>
<keywords>comedy,entertainment,women</keywords>
<talkid>1898</talkid>
<title>Maysoon Zayid: I got 99 problems... palsy is just one</title>
<seg id="1"> Hello, TEDWomen, what's up. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Not good enough. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Hello, TEDWomen, what is up? </seg>
<seg id="4"> My name is Maysoon Zayid, and I am not drunk, but the doctor who delivered me was. </seg>
<seg id="5"> He cut my mom six different times in six different directions, suffocating poor little me in the process. </seg>
<seg id="6"> As a result, I have cerebral palsy, which means I shake all the time. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Look. </seg>
<seg id="8"> It's exhausting. I'm like Shakira, Shakira meets Muhammad Ali. </seg>
<seg id="9"> C.P. is not genetic. </seg>
<seg id="10"> It's not a birth defect. You can't catch it. </seg>
<seg id="11"> No one put a curse on my mother's uterus, and I didn't get it because my parents are first cousins, which they are. </seg>
<seg id="12"> It only happens from accidents, like what happened to me on my birth day. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Now, I must warn you, I'm not inspirational, and I don't want anyone in this room to feel bad for me, because at some point in your life, you have dreamt of being disabled. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Come on a journey with me. </seg>
<seg id="15"> It's Christmas Eve, you're at the mall, you're driving around in circles looking for parking, and what do you see? </seg>
<seg id="16"> Sixteen empty handicapped spaces. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And you're like, "God, can't I just be a little disabled?" </seg>
<seg id="18"> Also, I gotta tell you, I got 99 problems, and palsy is just one. </seg>
<seg id="19"> If there was an Oppression Olympics, I would win the gold medal. </seg>
<seg id="20"> I'm Palestinian, Muslim, I'm female, I'm disabled, and I live in New Jersey. </seg>
<seg id="21"> If you don't feel better about yourself, maybe you should. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Cliffside Park, New Jersey is my hometown. </seg>
<seg id="23"> I have always loved the fact that my hood and my affliction share the same initials. </seg>
<seg id="24"> I also love the fact that if I wanted to walk from my house to New York City, I could. </seg>
<seg id="25"> A lot of people with C.P. don't walk, but my parents didn't believe in "can't." </seg>
<seg id="26"> My father's mantra was, "You can do it, yes you can can." </seg>
<seg id="27"> So, if my three older sisters were mopping, I was mopping. </seg>
<seg id="28"> If my three older sisters went to public school, my parents would sue the school system and guarantee that I went too, and if we didn't all get A's, we all got my mother's slipper. </seg>
<seg id="29"> My father taught me how to walk when I was five years old by placing my heels on his feet and just walking. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Another tactic that he used is he would dangle a dollar bill in front of me and have me chase it. </seg>
<seg id="31"> My inner stripper was very strong, and by -- Yeah. No, by the first day of kindergarten, I was walking like a champ who had been punched one too many times. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Growing up, there were only six Arabs in my town, and they were all my family. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Now there are 20 Arabs in town, and they are still all my family. </seg>
<seg id="34"> I don't think anyone even noticed we weren't Italian. </seg>
<seg id="35"> This was before 9/11 and before politicians thought it was appropriate to use "I hate Moslems" as a campaign slogan. </seg>
<seg id="36"> The people that I grew up with had no problem with my faith. </seg>
<seg id="37"> They did, however, seem very concerned that I would starve to death during Ramadan. </seg>
<seg id="38"> I would explain to them that I have enough fat to live off of for three whole months, so fasting from sunrise to sunset is a piece of cake. </seg>
<seg id="39"> I have tap-danced on Broadway. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Yeah, on Broadway. It's crazy. </seg>
<seg id="41"> My parents couldn't afford physical therapy, so they sent me to dancing school. </seg>
<seg id="42"> I learned how to dance in heels, which means I can walk in heels. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And I'm from Jersey, and we are really concerned with being chic, so if my friends wore heels, so did I. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And when my friends went and spent their summer vacations on the Jersey Shore, I did not. </seg>
<seg id="45"> I spent my summers in a war zone, because my parents were afraid that if we didn't go back to Palestine every single summer, we'd grow up to be Madonna. </seg>
<seg id="46"> Summer vacations often consisted of my father trying to heal me, so I drank deer's milk, I had hot cups on my back, I was dunked in the Dead Sea, and I remember the water burning my eyes and thinking, "It's working! It's working!" </seg>
<seg id="47"> But one miracle cure we did find was yoga. </seg>
<seg id="48"> I have to tell you, it's very boring, but before I did yoga, I was a stand-up comedian who can't stand up. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And now I can stand on my head. </seg>
<seg id="50"> My parents reinforced this notion that I could do anything, that no dream was impossible, and my dream was to be on the daytime soap opera "General Hospital." </seg>
<seg id="51"> I went to college during affirmative action and got a sweet scholarship to ASU, Arizona State University, because I fit every single quota. </seg>
<seg id="52"> I was like the pet lemur of the theater department. </seg>
<seg id="53"> Everybody loved me. </seg>
<seg id="54"> I did all the less-than-intelligent kids' homework, I got A's in all of my classes, A's in all of their classes. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Every time I did a scene from "The Glass Menagerie," my professors would weep. </seg>
<seg id="56"> But I never got cast. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Finally, my senior year, ASU decided to do a show called "They Dance Real Slow in Jackson." </seg>
<seg id="58"> It's a play about a girl with C.P. </seg>
<seg id="59"> I was a girl with C.P. </seg>
<seg id="60"> So I start shouting from the rooftops, "I'm finally going to get a part! </seg>
<seg id="61"> I have cerebral palsy! </seg>
<seg id="62"> Free at last! Free at last! </seg>
<seg id="63"> Thank God almighty, I'm free at last!" </seg>
<seg id="64"> I didn't get the part. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Sherry Brown got the part. </seg>
<seg id="66"> I went racing to the head of the theater department crying hysterically, like someone shot my cat, to ask her why, and she said it was because they didn't think I could do the stunts. </seg>
<seg id="67"> I said, "Excuse me, if I can't do the stunts, neither can the character." </seg>
<seg id="68"> This was a part that I was literally born to play and they gave it, they gave it to a non-palsy actress. </seg>
<seg id="69"> College was imitating life. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Hollywood has a sordid history of casting able-bodied actors to play disabled onscreen. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Upon graduating, I moved back home, and my first acting gig was as an extra on a daytime soap opera. </seg>
<seg id="72"> My dream was coming true. </seg>
<seg id="73"> And I knew that I would be promoted from "diner diner" to "wacky best friend" in no time. </seg>
<seg id="74"> But instead, I remained a glorified piece of furniture that you could only recognize from the back of my head, and it became clear to me that casting directors didn't hire fluffy, ethnic, disabled actors. </seg>
<seg id="75"> They only hired perfect people. </seg>
<seg id="76"> But there were exceptions to the rule. </seg>
<seg id="77"> I grew up watching Whoopi Goldberg, Roseanne Barr, Ellen, and all of these women had one thing in common: they were comedians. </seg>
<seg id="78"> So I became a comic. </seg>
<seg id="79"> My first gig was driving famous comics from New York City to shows in New Jersey, and I'll never forget the face of the first comic I ever drove when he realized that he was speeding down the New Jersey Turnpike with a chick with C.P. driving him. </seg>
<seg id="80"> I've performed in clubs all over America, and I've also performed in Arabic in the Middle East, uncensored and uncovered. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Some people say I'm the first stand-up comic in the Arab world. </seg>
<seg id="82"> I never like to claim first, but I do know that they never heard that nasty little rumor that women aren't funny, and they find us hysterical. </seg>
<seg id="83"> In 2003, my brother from another mother and father Dean Obeidallah and I started the New York Arab-American Comedy Festival, now in its 10th year. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Our goal was to change the negative image of Arab-Americans in media, while also reminding casting directors that South Asian and Arab are not synonymous. </seg>
<seg id="85"> Mainstreaming Arabs was much, much easier than conquering the challenge against the stigma against disability. </seg>
<seg id="86"> My big break came in 2010. </seg>
<seg id="87"> I was invited to be a guest on the cable news show "Countdown With Keith Olbermann." </seg>
<seg id="88"> I walked in looking like I was going to the prom, and they shuffle me into a studio and seat me on a spinning, rolling chair. </seg>
<seg id="89"> So I looked at the stage manager and I'm like, "Excuse me, can I have another chair?" </seg>
<seg id="90"> And she looked at me and she went, "Five, four, three, two ..." </seg>
<seg id="91"> And we were live, right? </seg>
<seg id="92"> So I had to grip onto the anchor's desk so that I wouldn't roll off the screen during the segment, and when the interview was over, I was livid. </seg>
<seg id="93"> I had finally gotten my chance and I blew it, and I knew I would never get invited back. </seg>
<seg id="94"> But not only did Mr. Olbermann invite me back, he made me a full-time contributor, and he taped down my chair. </seg>
<seg id="95"> One fun fact I learned while on the air with Keith Olbermann was that humans on the Internet are scumbags. </seg>
<seg id="96"> People say children are cruel, but I was never made fun of as a child or an adult. </seg>
<seg id="97"> Suddenly, my disability on the world wide web is fair game. </seg>
<seg id="98"> I would look at clips online and see comments like, "Yo, why's she tweakin?" </seg>
<seg id="99"> "Yo, is she retarded?" </seg>
<seg id="100"> And my favorite, "Poor Gumby-mouth terrorist. </seg>
<seg id="101"> What does she suffer from? </seg>
<seg id="102"> We should really pray for her." </seg>
<seg id="103"> One commenter even suggested that I add my disability to my credits: screenwriter, comedian, palsy. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Disability is as visual as race. </seg>
<seg id="105"> If a wheelchair user can't play Beyoncé, then Beyoncé can't play a wheelchair user. </seg>
<seg id="106"> The disabled are the largest — Yeah, clap for that, man. C'mon. </seg>
<seg id="107"> People with disabilities are the largest minority in the world, and we are the most underrepresented in entertainment. </seg>
<seg id="108"> The doctors said that I wouldn't walk, but I am here in front of you. </seg>
<seg id="109"> However, if I grew up with social media, I don't think I would be. </seg>
<seg id="110"> I hope that together we can create more positive images of disability in the media and in everyday life. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Perhaps if there were more positive images, it would foster less hate on the Internet. </seg>
<seg id="112"> Or maybe not. </seg>
<seg id="113"> Maybe it still takes a village to teach our children well. </seg>
<seg id="114"> My crooked journey has taken me to some very spectacular places. </seg>
<seg id="115"> I got to walk the red carpet flanked by soap diva Susan Lucci and the iconic Lorraine Arbus. </seg>
<seg id="116"> I got to act in a movie with Adam Sandler and work with my idol, the amazing Dave Matthews. </seg>
<seg id="117"> I toured the world as a headliner on Arabs Gone Wild. </seg>
<seg id="118"> I was a delegate representing the great state of New Jersey at the 2008 DNC. </seg>
<seg id="119"> And I founded Maysoon's Kids, a charity that hopes to give Palestinian refugee children a sliver of the chance my parents gave me. </seg>
<seg id="120"> But the one moment that stands out the most was when I got -- before this moment -- — but the one moment that stands out the most was when I got to perform for the man who floats like a butterfly and stings like a bee, has Parkinson's and shakes just like me, Muhammad Ali. </seg>
<seg id="121"> It was the only time that my father ever saw me perform live, and I dedicate this talk to his memory. </seg>
<seg id="122"> My name is Maysoon Zayid, and if I can can, you can can. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1835" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/jason_pontin_can_technology_solve_our_big_problems.html</url>
<description>In 1969, Buzz Aldrin's historical step onto the moon leapt mankind into an era of technological possibility. The awesome power of technology was to be used to solve all of our big problems. Fast forward to present day, and what's happened? Are mobile apps all we have to show for ourselves? Journalist Jason Pontin looks closely at the challenges we face to using technology effectively ... for problems that really matter.</description>
<keywords>NASA,astronomy,space,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1835</talkid>
<title> Can technology solve our big problems?</title>
<seg id="1"> So, we used to solve big problems. </seg>
<seg id="2"> On July 21st, 1969, Buzz Aldrin climbed out of Apollo 11's lunar module and descended onto the Sea of Tranquility. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Armstrong and Aldrin were alone, but their presence on the moon's gray surface was the culmination of a convulsive, collective effort. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The Apollo program was the greatest peacetime mobilization in the history of the United States. </seg>
<seg id="5"> To get to the moon, NASA spent around 180 billion dollars in today's money, or four percent of the federal budget. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Apollo employed around 400,000 people and demanded the collaboration of 20,000 companies, universities and government agencies. </seg>
<seg id="7"> People died, including the crew of Apollo 1. </seg>
<seg id="8"> But before the Apollo program ended, 24 men flew to the moon. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Twelve walked on its surface, of whom Aldrin, following the death of Armstrong last year, is now the most senior. </seg>
<seg id="10"> So why did they go? </seg>
<seg id="11"> They didn't bring much back: 841 pounds of old rocks, and something all 24 later emphasized -- a new sense of the smallness and the fragility of our common home. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Why did they go? The cynical answer is they went because President Kennedy wanted to show the Soviets that his nation had the better rockets. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But Kennedy's own words at Rice University in 1962 provide a better clue. </seg>
<seg id="14"> To contemporaries, Apollo wasn't only a victory of West over East in the Cold War. </seg>
<seg id="15"> At the time, the strongest emotion was of wonder at the transcendent powers of technology. </seg>
<seg id="16"> They went because it was a big thing to do. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Landing on the moon occurred in the context of a long series of technological triumphs. </seg>
<seg id="18"> The first half of the 20th century produced the assembly line and the airplane, penicillin and a vaccine for tuberculosis. </seg>
<seg id="19"> In the middle years of the century, polio was eradicated and smallpox eliminated. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Technology itself seemed to possess what Alvin Toffler in 1970 called "accelerative thrust." </seg>
<seg id="21"> For most of human history, we could go no faster than a horse or a boat with a sail, but in 1969, the crew of Apollo 10 flew at 25,000 miles an hour. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Since 1970, no human beings have been back to the moon. </seg>
<seg id="23"> No one has traveled faster than the crew of Apollo 10, and blithe optimism about technology's powers has evaporated as big problems we had imagined technology would solve, such as going to Mars, creating clean energy, curing cancer, or feeding the world have come to seem intractably hard. </seg>
<seg id="24"> I remember watching the liftoff of Apollo 17. </seg>
<seg id="25"> I was five years old, and my mother told me not to stare at the fiery exhaust of a Saturn V rocket. </seg>
<seg id="26"> I vaguely knew this was to be the last of the moon missions, but I was absolutely certain there would be Mars colonies in my lifetime. </seg>
<seg id="27"> So "Something happened to our capacity to solve big problems with technology" has become a commonplace. </seg>
<seg id="28"> You hear it all the time. </seg>
<seg id="29"> We've heard it over the last two days here at TED. </seg>
<seg id="30"> It feels as if technologists have diverted us and enriched themselves with trivial toys, with things like iPhones and apps and social media, or algorithms that speed automated trading. </seg>
<seg id="31"> There's nothing wrong with most of these things. </seg>
<seg id="32"> They've expanded and enriched our lives. </seg>
<seg id="33"> But they don't solve humanity's big problems. </seg>
<seg id="34"> What happened? </seg>
<seg id="35"> So there is a parochial explanation in Silicon Valley, which admits that it has been funding less ambitious companies than it did in the years when it financed Intel, Microsoft, Apple and Genentech. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Silicon Valley says the markets are to blame, in particular the incentives that venture capitalists offer to entrepreneurs. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Silicon Valley says that venture investing shifted away from funding transformational ideas and towards funding incremental problems or even fake problems. </seg>
<seg id="38"> But I don't think that explanation is good enough. </seg>
<seg id="39"> It mostly explains what's wrong with Silicon Valley. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Even when venture capitalists were at their most risk-happy, they preferred small investments, tiny investments that offered an exit within 10 years. </seg>
<seg id="41"> V.C.s have always struggled to invest profitably in technologies such as energy whose capital requirements are huge and whose development is long and lengthy, and V.C.s have never, never funded the development of technologies meant to solve big problems that possess no immediate commercial value. </seg>
<seg id="42"> No, the reasons we can't solve big problems are more complicated and more profound. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Sometimes we choose not to solve big problems. </seg>
<seg id="44"> We could go to Mars if we want. </seg>
<seg id="45"> NASA even has the outline of a plan. </seg>
<seg id="46"> But going to Mars would follow a political decision with popular appeal, and that will never happen. </seg>
<seg id="47"> We won't go to Mars, because everyone thinks there are more important things to do here on Earth. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Sometimes, we can't solve big problems because our political systems fail. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Today, less than two percent of the world's energy consumption derives from advanced, renewable sources such as solar, wind and biofuels, less than two percent, and the reason is purely economic. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Coal and natural gas are cheaper than solar and wind, and petroleum is cheaper than biofuels. </seg>
<seg id="51"> We want alternative energy sources that can compete on price. None exist. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Now, technologists, business leaders and economists all basically agree on what national policies and international treaties would spur the development of alternative energy: mostly, a significant increase in energy research and development, and some kind of price on carbon. </seg>
<seg id="53"> But there's no hope in the present political climate that we will see U.S. energy policy or international treaties that reflect that consensus. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Sometimes, big problems that had seemed technological turn out not to be so. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Famines were long understood to be caused by failures in food supply. </seg>
<seg id="56"> But 30 years of research have taught us that famines are political crises that catastrophically affect food distribution. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Technology can improve things like crop yields or systems for storing and transporting food, but there will be famines so long as there are bad governments. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Finally, big problems sometimes elude solution because we don't really understand the problem. </seg>
<seg id="59"> President Nixon declared war on cancer in 1971, but we soon discovered there are many kinds of cancer, most of them fiendishly resistant to therapy, and it is only in the last 10 years that effective, viable therapies have come to seem real. </seg>
<seg id="60"> Hard problems are hard. </seg>
<seg id="61"> It's not true that we can't solve big problems through technology. </seg>
<seg id="62"> We can, we must, but these four elements must all be present: Political leaders and the public must care to solve a problem; institutions must support its solution; It must really be a technological problem; and we must understand it. </seg>
<seg id="63"> The Apollo mission, which has become a kind of metaphor for technology's capacity to solve big problems, met these criteria. </seg>
<seg id="64"> But it is an irreproducible model for the future. </seg>
<seg id="65"> It is not 1961. </seg>
<seg id="66"> There is no galvanizing contest like the Cold War, no politician like John Kennedy who can heroize the difficult and the dangerous, and no popular science fictional mythology such as exploring the solar system. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Most of all, going to the moon turned out to be easy. </seg>
<seg id="68"> It was just three days away. </seg>
<seg id="69"> And arguably it wasn't even solving much of a problem. </seg>
<seg id="70"> We are left alone with our day, and the solutions of the future will be harder won. </seg>
<seg id="71"> God knows, we don't lack for the challenges. </seg>
<seg id="72"> Thank you very much. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1443" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/joshua_foer_feats_of_memory_anyone_can_do.html</url>
<description>There are people who can quickly memorize lists of thousands of numbers, the order of all the cards in a deck , and much more. Science writer Joshua Foer describes the technique -- called the memory palace -- and shows off its most remarkable feature: anyone can learn how to use it, including him.</description>
<keywords>brain,culture,memory,neuroscience,science</keywords>
<talkid>1443</talkid>
<title>Joshua Foer: Feats of memory anyone can do</title>
<seg id="1"> I'd like to invite you to close your eyes. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Imagine yourself standing outside the front door of your home. </seg>
<seg id="3"> I'd like you to notice the color of the door, the material that it's made out of. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Now visualize a pack of overweight nudists on bicycles. </seg>
<seg id="5"> They are competing in a naked bicycle race, and they are headed straight for your front door. </seg>
<seg id="6"> I need you to actually see this. </seg>
<seg id="7"> They are pedaling really hard, they're sweaty, they're bouncing around a lot. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And they crash straight into the front door of your home. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Bicycles fly everywhere, wheels roll past you, spokes end up in awkward places. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Step over the threshold of your door into your foyer, your hallway, whatever's on the other side, and appreciate the quality of the light. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The light is shining down on Cookie Monster. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Cookie Monster is waving at you from his perch on top of a tan horse. </seg>
<seg id="13"> It's a talking horse. </seg>
<seg id="14"> You can practically feel his blue fur tickling your nose. </seg>
<seg id="15"> You can smell the oatmeal raisin cookie that he's about to shovel into his mouth. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Walk past him. Walk past him into your living room. </seg>
<seg id="17"> In your living room, in full imaginative broadband, picture Britney Spears. </seg>
<seg id="18"> She is scantily clad, she's dancing on your coffee table, and she's singing "Hit Me Baby One More Time." </seg>
<seg id="19"> And then follow me into your kitchen. </seg>
<seg id="20"> In your kitchen, the floor has been paved over with a yellow brick road and out of your oven are coming towards you Dorothy, the Tin Man, the Scarecrow and the Lion from "The Wizard of Oz," hand-in-hand skipping straight towards you. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Okay. Open your eyes. </seg>
<seg id="22"> I want to tell you about a very bizarre contest that is held every spring in New York City. </seg>
<seg id="23"> It's called the United States Memory Championship. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And I had gone to cover this contest a few years back as a science journalist expecting, I guess, that this was going to be like the Superbowl of savants. </seg>
<seg id="25"> This was a bunch of guys and a few ladies, widely varying in both age and hygienic upkeep. </seg>
<seg id="26"> They were memorizing hundreds of random numbers, looking at them just once. </seg>
<seg id="27"> They were memorizing the names of dozens and dozens and dozens of strangers. </seg>
<seg id="28"> They were memorizing entire poems in just a few minutes. </seg>
<seg id="29"> They were competing to see who could memorize the order of a shuffled pack of playing cards the fastest. </seg>
<seg id="30"> I was like, this is unbelievable. </seg>
<seg id="31"> These people must be freaks of nature. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And I started talking to a few of the competitors. </seg>
<seg id="33"> This is a guy called Ed Cook who had come over from England where he had one of the best trained memories. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And I said to him, "Ed, when did you realize that you were a savant?" </seg>
<seg id="35"> And Ed was like, "I'm not a savant. </seg>
<seg id="36"> In fact, I have just an average memory. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Everybody who competes in this contest will tell you that they have just an average memory. </seg>
<seg id="38"> We've all trained ourselves to perform these utterly miraculous feats of memory using a set of ancient techniques, techniques invented 2,500 years ago in Greece, the same techniques that Cicero had used to memorize his speeches, that medieval scholars had used to memorize entire books." </seg>
<seg id="39"> And I was like, "Whoa. How come I never heard of this before?" </seg>
<seg id="40"> And we were standing outside the competition hall, and Ed, who is a wonderful, brilliant, but somewhat eccentric English guy, says to me, "Josh, you're an American journalist. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Do you know Britney Spears?" </seg>
<seg id="42"> I'm like, "What? No. Why?" </seg>
<seg id="43"> "Because I really want to teach Britney Spears how to memorize the order of a shuffled pack of playing cards on U.S. national television. </seg>
<seg id="44"> It will prove to the world that anybody can do this." </seg>
<seg id="45"> I was like, "Well I'm not Britney Spears, but maybe you could teach me. </seg>
<seg id="46"> I mean, you've got to start somewhere, right?" </seg>
<seg id="47"> And that was the beginning of a very strange journey for me. </seg>
<seg id="48"> I ended up spending the better part of the next year not only training my memory, but also investigating it, trying to understand how it works, why it sometimes doesn't work and what its potential might be. </seg>
<seg id="49"> I met a host of really interesting people. </seg>
<seg id="50"> This is a guy called E.P. </seg>
<seg id="51"> He's an amnesic who had, very possibly, the very worst memory in the world. </seg>
<seg id="52"> His memory was so bad that he didn't even remember he had a memory problem, which is amazing. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And he was this incredibly tragic figure, but he was a window into the extent to which our memories make us who we are. </seg>
<seg id="54"> The other end of the spectrum: I met this guy. </seg>
<seg id="55"> This is Kim Peek. </seg>
<seg id="56"> He was the basis for Dustin Hoffman's character in the movie "Rain Man." </seg>
<seg id="57"> We spent an afternoon together in the Salt Lake City Public Library memorizing phone books, which was scintillating. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And I went back and I read a whole host of memory treatises, treatises written 2,000-plus years ago in Latin in Antiquity and then later in the Middle Ages. </seg>
<seg id="59"> And I learned a whole bunch of really interesting stuff. </seg>
<seg id="60"> One of the really interesting things that I learned is that once upon a time, this idea of having a trained, disciplined, cultivated memory was not nearly so alien as it would seem to us to be today. </seg>
<seg id="61"> Once upon a time, people invested in their memories, in laboriously furnishing their minds. </seg>
<seg id="62"> Over the last few millenia we've invented a series of technologies -- from the alphabet to the scroll to the codex, the printing press, photography, the computer, the smartphone -- that have made it progressively easier and easier for us to externalize our memories, for us to essentially outsource this fundamental human capacity. </seg>
<seg id="63"> These technologies have made our modern world possible, but they've also changed us. </seg>
<seg id="64"> They've changed us culturally, and I would argue that they've changed us cognitively. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Having little need to remember anymore, it sometimes seems like we've forgotten how. </seg>
<seg id="66"> One of the last places on Earth where you still find people passionate about this idea of a trained, disciplined, cultivated memory is at this totally singular memory contest. </seg>
<seg id="67"> It's actually not that singular, there are contests held all over the world. </seg>
<seg id="68"> And I was fascinated, I wanted to know how do these guys do it. </seg>
<seg id="69"> A few years back a group of researchers at University College London brought a bunch of memory champions into the lab. </seg>
<seg id="70"> They wanted to know: Do these guys have brains that are somehow structurally, anatomically different from the rest of ours? </seg>
<seg id="71"> The answer was no. </seg>
<seg id="72"> Are they smarter than the rest of us? </seg>
<seg id="73"> They gave them a bunch of cognitive tests, and the answer was not really. </seg>
<seg id="74"> There was however one really interesting and telling difference between the brains of the memory champions and the control subjects that they were comparing them to. </seg>
<seg id="75"> When they put these guys in an fMRI machine, scanned their brains while they were memorizing numbers and people's faces and pictures of snowflakes, they found that the memory champions were lighting up different parts of the brain than everyone else. </seg>
<seg id="76"> Of note, they were using, or they seemed to be using, a part of the brain that's involved in spatial memory and navigation. </seg>
<seg id="77"> Why? And is there something the rest of us can learn from this? </seg>
<seg id="78"> The sport of competitive memorizing is driven by a kind of arms race where every year somebody comes up with a new way to remember more stuff more quickly, and then the rest of the field has to play catchup. </seg>
<seg id="79"> This is my friend Ben Pridmore, three-time world memory champion. </seg>
<seg id="80"> On his desk in front of him are 36 shuffled packs of playing cards that he is about to try to memorize in one hour, using a technique that he invented and he alone has mastered. </seg>
<seg id="81"> He used a similar technique to memorize the precise order of 4,140 random binary digits in half an hour. </seg>
<seg id="82"> Yeah. </seg>
<seg id="83"> And while there are a whole host of ways of remembering stuff in these competitions, everything, all of the techniques that are being used, ultimately come down to a concept that psychologists refer to as elaborative encoding. </seg>
<seg id="84"> And it's well illustrated by a nifty paradox known as the Baker/baker paradox, which goes like this: If I tell two people to remember the same word, if I say to you, "Remember that there is a guy named Baker." </seg>
<seg id="85"> That's his name. </seg>
<seg id="86"> And I say to you, "Remember that there is a guy who is a baker." </seg>
<seg id="87"> And I come back to you at some point later on, and I say, "Do you remember that word that I told you a while back? </seg>
<seg id="88"> Do you remember what it was?" </seg>
<seg id="89"> The person who was told his name is Baker is less likely to remember the same word than the person was told his job is that he is a baker. </seg>
<seg id="90"> Same word, different amount of remembering; that's weird. </seg>
<seg id="91"> What's going on here? </seg>
<seg id="92"> Well the name Baker doesn't actually mean anything to you. </seg>
<seg id="93"> It is entirely untethered from all of the other memories floating around in your skull. </seg>
<seg id="94"> But the common noun baker, we know bakers. </seg>
<seg id="95"> Bakers wear funny white hats. </seg>
<seg id="96"> Bakers have flour on their hands. </seg>
<seg id="97"> Bakers smell good when they come home from work. </seg>
<seg id="98"> Maybe we even know a baker. </seg>
<seg id="99"> And when we first hear that word, we start putting these associational hooks into it that make it easier to fish it back out at some later date. </seg>
<seg id="100"> The entire art of what is going on in these memory contests and the entire art of remembering stuff better in everyday life is figuring out ways to transform capital B Bakers into lower-case B bakers -- to take information that is lacking in context, in significance, in meaning and transform it in some way so that it becomes meaningful in the light of all the other things that you have in your mind. </seg>
<seg id="101"> One of the more elaborate techniques for doing this dates back 2,500 years to Ancient Greece. </seg>
<seg id="102"> It came to be known as the memory palace. </seg>
<seg id="103"> The story behind its creation goes like this: There was a poet called Simonides who was attending a banquet. </seg>
<seg id="104"> He was actually the hired entertainment, because back then if you wanted to throw a really slamming party, you didn't hire a D.J., you hired a poet. </seg>
<seg id="105"> And he stands up, delivers his poem from memory, walks out the door, and at the moment he does, the banquet hall collapses, kills everybody inside. </seg>
<seg id="106"> It doesn't just kill everybody, it mangles the bodies beyond all recognition. </seg>
<seg id="107"> Nobody can say who was inside, nobody can say where they were sitting. </seg>
<seg id="108"> The bodies can't be properly buried. </seg>
<seg id="109"> It's one tragedy compounding another. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Simonides, standing outside, the sole survivor amid the wreckage, closes his eyes and has this realization, which is that in his mind's eye, he can see where each of the guests at the banquet had been sitting. </seg>
<seg id="111"> And he takes the relatives by the hand and guides them each to their loved ones amid the wreckage. </seg>
<seg id="112"> What Simonides figured out at that moment is something that I think we all kind of intuitively know, which is that, as bad as we are at remembering names and phone numbers and word-for-word instructions from our colleagues, we have really exceptional visual and spatial memories. </seg>
<seg id="113"> If I asked you to recount the first 10 words of the story that I just told you about Simonides, chances are you would have a tough time with it. </seg>
<seg id="114"> But I would wager that if I asked you to recall who is sitting on top of a talking tan horse in your foyer right now, you would be able to see that. </seg>
<seg id="115"> The idea behind the memory palace is to create this imagined edifice in your mind's eye and populate it with images of the things that you want to remember -- the crazier, weirder, more bizarre, funnier, raunchier, stinkier the image is, the more unforgettable it's likely to be. </seg>
<seg id="116"> This is advice that goes back 2,000-plus years to the earliest Latin memory treatises. </seg>
<seg id="117"> So how does this work? </seg>
<seg id="118"> Let's say that you've been invited to TED center stage to give a speech and you want to do it from memory, and you want to do it the way that Cicero would have done it if he had been invited to TEDxRome 2,000 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="119"> What you might do is picture yourself at the front door of your house. </seg>
<seg id="120"> And you'd come up with some sort of an absolutely crazy, ridiculous, unforgettable image to remind you that the first thing you want to talk about is this totally bizarre contest. </seg>
<seg id="121"> And then you'd go inside your house, and you would see an image of Cookie Monster on top of Mister Ed. </seg>
<seg id="122"> And that would remind you that you would want to then introduce your friend Ed Cook. </seg>
<seg id="123"> And then you'd see an image of Britney Spears to remind you of this funny anecdote you want to tell. </seg>
<seg id="124"> And you go into your kitchen, and the fourth topic you were going to talk about was this strange journey that you went on for a year, and you have some friends to help you remember that. </seg>
<seg id="125"> This is how Roman orators memorized their speeches -- not word-for-word, which is just going to screw you up, but topic-for-topic. </seg>
<seg id="126"> In fact, the phrase "topic sentence," that comes from the Greek word "topos," which means "place." </seg>
<seg id="127"> That's a vestige of when people used to think about oratory and rhetoric in these sorts of spatial terms. </seg>
<seg id="128"> The phrase "in the first place," that's like in the first place of your memory palace. </seg>
<seg id="129"> I thought this was just fascinating, and I got really into it. </seg>
<seg id="130"> And I went to a few more of these memory contests. </seg>
<seg id="131"> And I had this notion that I might write something longer about this subculture of competitive memorizers. </seg>
<seg id="132"> But there was a problem. </seg>
<seg id="133"> The problem was that a memory contest is a pathologically boring event. </seg>
<seg id="134"> Truly, it is like a bunch of people sitting around taking the SATs. </seg>
<seg id="135"> I mean, the most dramatic it gets is when somebody starts massaging their temples. </seg>
<seg id="136"> And I'm a journalist, I need something to write about. </seg>
<seg id="137"> I know that there's this incredible stuff happening in these people's minds, but I don't have access to it. </seg>
<seg id="138"> And I realized, if I was going to tell this story, I needed to walk in their shoes a little bit. </seg>
<seg id="139"> And so I started trying to spend 15 or 20 minutes every morning before I sat down with my New York Times just trying to remember something. </seg>
<seg id="140"> Maybe it was a poem. </seg>
<seg id="141"> Maybe it was names from an old yearbook that I bought at a flea market. </seg>
<seg id="142"> And I found that this was shockingly fun. </seg>
<seg id="143"> I never would have expected that. </seg>
<seg id="144"> It was fun because this is actually not about training your memory. </seg>
<seg id="145"> What you're doing is you're trying to get better and better and better at creating, at dreaming up, these utterly ludicrous, raunchy, hilarious and hopefully unforgettable images in your mind's eye. </seg>
<seg id="146"> And I got pretty into it. </seg>
<seg id="147"> This is me wearing my standard competitive memorizer's training kit. </seg>
<seg id="148"> It's a pair of earmuffs and a set of safety goggles that have been masked over except for two small pinholes, because distraction is the competitive memorizer's greatest enemy. </seg>
<seg id="149"> I ended up coming back to that same contest that I had covered a year earlier. </seg>
<seg id="150"> And I had this notion that I might enter it, sort of as an experiment in participatory journalism. </seg>
<seg id="151"> It'd make, I thought, maybe a nice epilogue to all my research. </seg>
<seg id="152"> Problem was the experiment went haywire. </seg>
<seg id="153"> I won the contest, which really wasn't supposed to happen. </seg>
<seg id="154"> Now it is nice to be able to memorize speeches and phone numbers and shopping lists, but it's actually kind of beside the point. </seg>
<seg id="155"> These are just tricks. </seg>
<seg id="156"> They are tricks that work because they're based on some pretty basic principles about how our brains work. </seg>
<seg id="157"> And you don't have to be building memory palaces or memorizing packs of playing cards to benefit from a little bit of insight about how your mind works. </seg>
<seg id="158"> We often talk about people with great memories as though it were some sort of an innate gift, but that is not the case. </seg>
<seg id="159"> Great memories are learned. </seg>
<seg id="160"> At the most basic level, we remember when we pay attention. </seg>
<seg id="161"> We remember when we are deeply engaged. </seg>
<seg id="162"> We remember when we are able to take a piece of information and experience and figure out why it is meaningful to us, why it is significant, why it's colorful, when we're able to transform it in some way that it makes sense in the light of all of the other things floating around in our minds, when we're able to transform Bakers into bakers. </seg>
<seg id="163"> The memory palace, these memory techniques, they're just shortcuts. </seg>
<seg id="164"> In fact, they're not even really shortcuts. </seg>
<seg id="165"> They work because they make you work. </seg>
<seg id="166"> They force a kind of depth of processing, a kind of mindfulness, that most of us don't normally walk around exercising. </seg>
<seg id="167"> But there actually are no shortcuts. </seg>
<seg id="168"> This is how stuff is made memorable. </seg>
<seg id="169"> And I think if there's one thing that I want to leave you with, it's what E.P., the amnesic who couldn't even remember that he had a memory problem, left me with, which is the notion that our lives are the sum of our memories. </seg>
<seg id="170"> How much are we willing to lose from our already short lives by losing ourselves in our Blackberries, our iPhones, by not paying attention to the human being across from us who is talking with us, by being so lazy that we're not willing to process deeply? </seg>
<seg id="171"> I learned firsthand that there are incredible memory capacities latent in all of us. </seg>
<seg id="172"> But if you want to live a memorable life, you have to be the kind of person who remembers to remember. </seg>
<seg id="173"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1733" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/angela_lee_duckworth_the_key_to_success_grit.html</url>
<description>Leaving a high-flying job in consulting, Angela Lee Duckworth took a job teaching math to seventh graders in a New York public school. She quickly realized that IQ wasn't the only thing separating the successful students from those who struggled. Here, she explains her theory of "grit" as a predictor of success.</description>
<keywords>business,education,psychology,success</keywords>
<talkid>1733</talkid>
<title>Angela Lee Duckworth: The key to success? Grit</title>
<seg id="1"> When I was 27 years old, I left a very demanding job in management consulting for a job that was even more demanding: teaching. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I went to teach seventh graders math in the New York City public schools. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And like any teacher, I made quizzes and tests. </seg>
<seg id="4"> I gave out homework assignments. </seg>
<seg id="5"> When the work came back, I calculated grades. </seg>
<seg id="6"> What struck me was that I.Q. was not the only difference between my best and my worst students. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Some of my strongest performers did not have stratospheric I.Q. scores. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Some of my smartest kids weren't doing so well. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And that got me thinking. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The kinds of things you need to learn in seventh grade math, sure, they're hard: ratios, decimals, the area of a parallelogram. </seg>
<seg id="11"> But these concepts are not impossible, and I was firmly convinced that every one of my students could learn the material if they worked hard and long enough. </seg>
<seg id="12"> After several more years of teaching, I came to the conclusion that what we need in education is a much better understanding of students and learning from a motivational perspective, from a psychological perspective. </seg>
<seg id="13"> In education, the one thing we know how to measure best is I.Q., but what if doing well in school and in life depends on much more than your ability to learn quickly and easily? </seg>
<seg id="14"> So I left the classroom, and I went to graduate school to become a psychologist. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I started studying kids and adults in all kinds of super challenging settings, and in every study my question was, who is successful here and why? </seg>
<seg id="16"> My research team and I went to West Point Military Academy. </seg>
<seg id="17"> We tried to predict which cadets would stay in military training and which would drop out. </seg>
<seg id="18"> We went to the National Spelling Bee and tried to predict which children would advance farthest in competition. </seg>
<seg id="19"> We studied rookie teachers working in really tough neighborhoods, asking which teachers are still going to be here in teaching by the end of the school year, and of those, who will be the most effective at improving learning outcomes for their students? </seg>
<seg id="20"> We partnered with private companies, asking, which of these salespeople is going to keep their jobs? </seg>
<seg id="21"> And who's going to earn the most money? </seg>
<seg id="22"> In all those very different contexts, one characteristic emerged as a significant predictor of success. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And it wasn't social intelligence. </seg>
<seg id="24"> It wasn't good looks, physical health, and it wasn't I.Q. </seg>
<seg id="25"> It was grit. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Grit is passion and perseverance for very long-term goals. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Grit is having stamina. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Grit is sticking with your future, day in, day out, not just for the week, not just for the month, but for years, and working really hard to make that future a reality. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Grit is living life like it's a marathon, not a sprint. </seg>
<seg id="30"> A few years ago, I started studying grit in the Chicago public schools. </seg>
<seg id="31"> I asked thousands of high school juniors to take grit questionnaires, and then waited around more than a year to see who would graduate. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Turns out that grittier kids were significantly more likely to graduate, even when I matched them on every characteristic I could measure, things like family income, standardized achievement test scores, even how safe kids felt when they were at school. </seg>
<seg id="33"> So it's not just at West Point or the National Spelling Bee that grit matters. It's also in school, especially for kids at risk for dropping out. </seg>
<seg id="34"> To me, the most shocking thing about grit is how little we know, how little science knows, about building it. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Every day, parents and teachers ask me, "How do I build grit in kids? </seg>
<seg id="36"> What do I do to teach kids a solid work ethic? </seg>
<seg id="37"> How do I keep them motivated for the long run?" </seg>
<seg id="38"> The honest answer is, I don't know. </seg>
<seg id="39"> What I do know is that talent doesn't make you gritty. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Our data show very clearly that there are many talented individuals who simply do not follow through on their commitments. </seg>
<seg id="41"> In fact, in our data, grit is usually unrelated or even inversely related to measures of talent. </seg>
<seg id="42"> So far, the best idea I've heard about building grit in kids is something called "growth mindset." </seg>
<seg id="43"> This is an idea developed at Stanford University by Carol Dweck, and it is the belief that the ability to learn is not fixed, that it can change with your effort. </seg>
<seg id="44"> Dr. Dweck has shown that when kids read and learn about the brain and how it changes and grows in response to challenge, they're much more likely to persevere when they fail, because they don't believe that failure is a permanent condition. </seg>
<seg id="45"> So growth mindset is a great idea for building grit. </seg>
<seg id="46"> But we need more. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And that's where I'm going to end my remarks, because that's where we are. </seg>
<seg id="48"> That's the work that stands before us. </seg>
<seg id="49"> We need to take our best ideas, our strongest intuitions, and we need to test them. </seg>
<seg id="50"> We need to measure whether we've been successful, and we have to be willing to fail, to be wrong, to start over again with lessons learned. </seg>
<seg id="51"> In other words, we need to be gritty about getting our kids grittier. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1854" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/xavier_vilalta_architecture_at_home_in_its_community.html</url>
<description>When Fellow Xavier Vilalta was commissioned to create a multistory shopping mall in Addis Ababa, he panicked. Other centers represented everything he hated about contemporary architecture: wasteful, glass towers requiring tons of energy whose design had absolutely nothing to do with Africa. In this charming talk, Vilalta shows how he champions an alternative approach: to harness nature, reference design tradition and create beautiful, modern, iconic buildings fit for a community.</description>
<keywords>Africa,TED Fellows,architecture,design</keywords>
<talkid>1854</talkid>
<title>Xavier Vilalta: Architecture at home in its community</title>
<seg id="1"> My work focuses on the connection of both thinking about our community life being part of the environment where architecture grows from the natural local conditions and traditions. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Today I brought two recent projects as an example of this. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Both projects are in emerging countries, one in Ethiopia and another one in Tunisia. </seg>
<seg id="4"> And also they have in common that the different analyses from different perspectives becomes an essential part of the final piece of architecture. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The first example started with an invitation to design a multistory shopping mall in Ethiopia's capital city Addis Ababa. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And this is the type of building we were shown as an example, to my team and myself, of what we had to design. </seg>
<seg id="7"> At first, the first thing I thought was, I want to run away. </seg>
<seg id="8"> After seeing a few of these buildings -- there are many in the city -- we realized that they have three very big points. </seg>
<seg id="9"> First, these buildings, they are almost empty because they have very large shops where people cannot afford to buy things. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Second, they need tons of energy to perform because of the skin treatment with glass that creates heat in the inside, and then you need a lot of cooling. </seg>
<seg id="11"> In a city where this shouldn't happen because they have really mild weather that ranges from 20 to 25 degrees the whole year. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And third is that their image has nothing to do with Africa and with Ethiopia. </seg>
<seg id="13"> It is a pity in a place that has such rich culture and traditions. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Also during our first visit to Ethiopia, I was really captivated by the old merkato that is this open-air structure where thousands of people, they go and buy things every day from small vendors. </seg>
<seg id="15"> And also it has this idea of the public space that uses the outdoors to create activity. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So I thought, this is what I really want to design, not a shopping mall. </seg>
<seg id="17"> But the question was how we could do a multistory, contemporary building with these principles. </seg>
<seg id="18"> The next challenge was when we looked at the site, that is, in a really growing area of the city, where most of these buildings that you see in the image, they were not there. </seg>
<seg id="19"> And it's also between two parallel streets that don't have any connection for hundreds of meters. </seg>
<seg id="20"> So the first thing we did was to create a connection between these two streets, putting all the entrances of the building. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And this extends with an inclined atrium that creates an open-air space in the building that self-protects itself with its own shape from the sun and the rain. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And around this void we placed this idea of the market with small shops, that change in each floor because of the shape of the void. </seg>
<seg id="23"> I also thought, how to close the building? </seg>
<seg id="24"> And I really wanted to find a solution that would respond to the local climate conditions. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And I started thinking about the textile like a shell made of concrete with perforations that would let the air in, and also the light, but in a filtered way. </seg>
<seg id="26"> And then the inspiration came from these beautiful buttons of the Ethiopian women's dresses. </seg>
<seg id="27"> That they have fractal geometry properties and this helped me to shape the whole facade. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And we are building that with these small prefabricated pieces that are the windows that let the air and the light in a controlled way inside the building. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And this is complemented by these small colored glasses that use the light from the inside of the building to light up the building at night. </seg>
<seg id="30"> With these ideas it was not easy first to convince the developers because they were like, "This is not a shopping mall. We didn't ask for that." </seg>
<seg id="31"> But then we all realized that this idea of the market happened to be a lot more profitable than the idea of the shopping mall because basically they had more shops to sell. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And also that the idea of the facade was much, much cheaper, not only because of the material compared with the glass, but also because we didn't need to have air conditioning anymore. </seg>
<seg id="33"> So we created some budget savings that we used to implement the project. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And the first implementation was to think about how we could make the building self-sufficient in terms of energy in a city that has electricity cuts almost every day. </seg>
<seg id="35"> So we created a huge asset by placing photovoltaics there on the roof. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And then under those panels we thought about the roof like a new public space with gathering areas and bars that would create this urban oasis. </seg>
<seg id="37"> And these porches on the roof, all together they collect the water to reuse for sanitation on the inside. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Hopefully by the beginning of next year, because we are already on the fifth floor of the construction. </seg>
<seg id="39"> The second example is a master plan of 2,000 apartments and facilities in the city of Tunis. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And for doing such a big project, the biggest project I've ever designed, I really needed to understand the city of Tunis, but also its surroundings and the tradition and culture. </seg>
<seg id="41"> During that analysis I paid special attention to the medina that is this 1,000-year-old structure that used to be closed by a wall, opened by twelve different gates, connected by almost straight lines. </seg>
<seg id="42"> When I went to the site, the first design operation we did was to extend the existing streets, creating 12 initial blocks similar in size and characteristics to the ones we have in Barcelona and other cities in Europe with these courtyards. </seg>
<seg id="43"> On top of that, we selected some strategic points reminded of this idea of the gates and connecting them by straight lines, and this modified this initial pattern. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And the last operation was to think about the cell, the small cell of the project, like the apartment, as an essential part of the master plan. </seg>
<seg id="45"> And for that I thought, what would be the best orientation in the Mediterranean climate for an apartment? </seg>
<seg id="46"> And it's north-south, because it creates a thermal difference between both sides of the house and then a natural ventilation. </seg>
<seg id="47"> So we overlap a pattern that makes sure that most of the apartments are perfectly oriented in that direction. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And this is the result that is almost like a combination of the European block and the Arab city. </seg>
<seg id="49"> It has these blocks with courtyards, and then on the ground floor you have all these connections for the pedestrians. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And also it responds to the local regulations that establish a higher density on the upper levels and a lower density on the ground floor. </seg>
<seg id="51"> And it also reinforces this idea of the gates. </seg>
<seg id="52"> The volume has this connecting shape that shades itself with three different types of apartments and also lets the light go on the ground floor in a very dense neighborhood And in the courtyards there are the different facilities, such as a gym and a kindergarten and close by, a series of commercial [spaces] that bring activity to the ground floor. </seg>
<seg id="53"> The roof, which is my favorite space of the project is almost like giving back to the community the space taken by the construction. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And it's where all the neighbors, they can go up and socialize, and do activities such as having a two-kilometer run in the morning, jumping from one building to another. </seg>
<seg id="55"> These two examples, they have a common approach in the design process. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And also, they are in emerging countries where you can see the cities literally growing. </seg>
<seg id="57"> In these cities, the impact of architecture in people's lives of today and tomorrow changes the local communities and economies at the same speed as the buildings grow. </seg>
<seg id="58"> For this reason, I see even more importance to look at architecture finding simple but affordable solutions that enhance the relationship between the community and the environment and that aim to connect nature and people. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Thank you very much. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1829" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/onora_o_neill_what_we_don_t_understand_about_trust.html</url>
<description>Trust is on the decline, and we need to rebuild it. That's a commonly heard suggestion for making a better world … but, says philosopher Onora O'Neill, we don't really understand what we're suggesting. She flips the question, showing us that our three most common ideas about trust are actually misdirected. &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
<keywords>global issues,government,philosophy,politics</keywords>
<talkid>1829</talkid>
<title>Onora O'Neill: What we don't understand about trust</title>
<seg id="1"> So I'm going to talk about trust, and I'm going to start by reminding you of the standard views that people have about trust. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I think these are so commonplace, they've become clichés of our society. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And I think there are three. </seg>
<seg id="4"> One's a claim: there has been a great decline in trust, very widely believed. </seg>
<seg id="5"> The second is an aim: we should have more trust. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And the third is a task: we should rebuild trust. </seg>
<seg id="7"> I think that the claim, the aim and the task are all misconceived. </seg>
<seg id="8"> So what I'm going to try to tell you today is a different story about a claim, an aim and a task which I think give one quite a lot better purchase on the matter. </seg>
<seg id="9"> First the claim: Why do people think trust has declined? </seg>
<seg id="10"> And if I really think about it on the basis of my own evidence, I don't know the answer. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I'm inclined to think it may have declined in some activities or some institutions and it might have grown in others. </seg>
<seg id="12"> I don't have an overview. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But, of course, I can look at the opinion polls, and the opinion polls are supposedly the source of a belief that trust has declined. </seg>
<seg id="14"> When you actually look at opinion polls across time, there's not much evidence for that. </seg>
<seg id="15"> That's to say, the people who were mistrusted 20 years ago, principally journalists and politicians, are still mistrusted. </seg>
<seg id="16"> And the people who were highly trusted 20 years ago are still rather highly trusted: judges, nurses. </seg>
<seg id="17"> The rest of us are in between, and by the way, the average person in the street is almost exactly midway. </seg>
<seg id="18"> But is that good evidence? </seg>
<seg id="19"> What opinion polls record is, of course, opinions. </seg>
<seg id="20"> What else can they record? </seg>
<seg id="21"> So they're looking at the generic attitudes that people report when you ask them certain questions. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Do you trust politicians? Do you trust teachers? </seg>
<seg id="23"> Now if somebody said to you, "Do you trust greengrocers? </seg>
<seg id="24"> Do you trust fishmongers? </seg>
<seg id="25"> Do you trust elementary school teachers?" </seg>
<seg id="26"> you would probably begin by saying, "To do what?" </seg>
<seg id="27"> And that would be a perfectly sensible response. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And you might say, when you understood the answer to that, "Well, I trust some of them, but not others." </seg>
<seg id="29"> That's a perfectly rational thing. </seg>
<seg id="30"> In short, in our real lives, we seek to place trust in a differentiated way. </seg>
<seg id="31"> We don't make an assumption that the level of trust that we will have in every instance of a certain type of official or office-holder or type of person is going to be uniform. </seg>
<seg id="32"> I might, for example, say that I certainly trust a certain elementary school teacher I know to teach the reception class to read, but in no way to drive the school minibus. </seg>
<seg id="33"> I might, after all, know that she wasn't a good driver. </seg>
<seg id="34"> I might trust my most loquacious friend to keep a conversation going but not -- but perhaps not to keep a secret. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Simple. </seg>
<seg id="36"> So if we've got those evidence in our ordinary lives of the way that trust is differentiated, why do we sort of drop all that intelligence when we think about trust more abstractly? </seg>
<seg id="37"> I think the polls are very bad guides to the level of trust that actually exists, because they try to obliterate the good judgment that goes into placing trust. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Secondly, what about the aim? </seg>
<seg id="39"> The aim is to have more trust. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Well frankly, I think that's a stupid aim. </seg>
<seg id="41"> It's not what I would aim at. </seg>
<seg id="42"> I would aim to have more trust in the trustworthy but not in the untrustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="43"> In fact, I aim positively to try not to trust the untrustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And I think, of those people who, for example, placed their savings with the very aptly named Mr. Madoff, who then made off with them, and I think of them, and I think, well, yes, too much trust. </seg>
<seg id="45"> More trust is not an intelligent aim in this life. </seg>
<seg id="46"> Intelligently placed and intelligently refused trust is the proper aim. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Well once one says that, one says, yeah, okay, that means that what matters in the first place is not trust but trustworthiness. </seg>
<seg id="48"> It's judging how trustworthy people are in particular respects. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And I think that judgment requires us to look at three things. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Are they competent? Are they honest? Are they reliable? </seg>
<seg id="51"> And if we find that a person is competent in the relevant matters, and reliable and honest, we'll have a pretty good reason to trust them, because they'll be trustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="52"> But if, on the other hand, they're unreliable, we might not. </seg>
<seg id="53"> I have friends who are competent and honest, but I would not trust them to post a letter, because they're forgetful. </seg>
<seg id="54"> I have friends who are very confident they can do certain things, but I realize that they overestimate their own competence. </seg>
<seg id="55"> And I'm very glad to say, I don't think I have many friends who are competent and reliable but extremely dishonest. </seg>
<seg id="56"> If so, I haven't yet spotted it. </seg>
<seg id="57"> But that's what we're looking for: trustworthiness before trust. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Trust is the response. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Trustworthiness is what we have to judge. And, of course, it's difficult. </seg>
<seg id="60"> Across the last few decades, we've tried to construct systems of accountability for all sorts of institutions and professionals and officials and so on that will make it easier for us to judge their trustworthiness. </seg>
<seg id="61"> A lot of these systems have the converse effect. </seg>
<seg id="62"> They don't work as they're supposed to. </seg>
<seg id="63"> I remember I was talking with a midwife who said, "Well, you see, the problem is it takes longer to do the paperwork than to deliver the baby." </seg>
<seg id="64"> And all over our public life, our institutional life, we find that problem, that the system of accountability that is meant to secure trustworthiness and evidence of trustworthiness is actually doing the opposite. </seg>
<seg id="65"> It is distracting people who have to do difficult tasks, like midwives, from doing them by requiring them to tick the boxes, as we say. </seg>
<seg id="66"> You can all give your own examples there. </seg>
<seg id="67"> So so much for the aim. </seg>
<seg id="68"> The aim, I think, is more trustworthiness, and that is going to be different if we are trying to be trustworthy and communicate our trustworthiness to other people, and if we are trying to judge whether other people or office-holders or politicians are trustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="69"> It's not easy. It is judgment, and simple reaction, attitudes, don't do adequately here. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Now thirdly, the task. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Calling the task rebuilding trust, I think, also gets things backwards. </seg>
<seg id="72"> It suggests that you and I should rebuild trust. </seg>
<seg id="73"> Well, we can do that for ourselves. </seg>
<seg id="74"> We can rebuild a bit of trustworthiness. </seg>
<seg id="75"> We can do it two people together trying to improve trust. </seg>
<seg id="76"> But trust, in the end, is distinctive because it's given by other people. </seg>
<seg id="77"> You can't rebuild what other people give you. </seg>
<seg id="78"> You have to give them the basis for giving you their trust. </seg>
<seg id="79"> So you have to, I think, be trustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="80"> And that, of course, is because you can't fool all of the people all of the time, usually. </seg>
<seg id="81"> But you also have to provide usable evidence that you are trustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="82"> How to do it? </seg>
<seg id="83"> Well every day, all over the place, it's being done by ordinary people, by officials, by institutions, quite effectively. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Let me give you a simple commercial example. </seg>
<seg id="85"> The shop where I buy my socks says I may take them back, and they don't ask any questions. </seg>
<seg id="86"> They take them back and give me the money or give me the pair of socks of the color I wanted. </seg>
<seg id="87"> That's super. I trust them because they have made themselves vulnerable to me. </seg>
<seg id="88"> I think there's a big lesson in that. </seg>
<seg id="89"> If you make yourself vulnerable to the other party, then that is very good evidence that you are trustworthy and you have confidence in what you are saying. </seg>
<seg id="90"> So in the end, I think what we are aiming for is not very difficult to discern. </seg>
<seg id="91"> It is relationships in which people are trustworthy and can judge when and how the other person is trustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="92"> So the moral of all this is, we need to think much less about trust, let alone about attitudes of trust detected or mis-detected by opinion polls, much more about being trustworthy, and how you give people adequate, useful and simple evidence that you're trustworthy. </seg>
<seg id="93"> Thanks. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1650" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/colin_stokes_how_movies_teach_manhood.html</url>
<description>When Colin Stokes' 3-year-old son caught a glimpse of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, he was instantly obsessed. But what messages did he absorb from the sci-fi classic? Stokes asks for more movies that send positive messages to boys: that cooperation is heroic, and respecting women is as manly as defeating the villain. </description>
<keywords>culture,film,parenting</keywords>
<talkid>1650</talkid>
<title>Colin Stokes: How movies teach manhood</title>
<seg id="1"> You know, my favorite part of being a dad is the movies I get to watch. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I love sharing my favorite movies with my kids, and when my daughter was four, we got to watch "The Wizard of Oz" together. </seg>
<seg id="3"> It totally dominated her imagination for months. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Her favorite character was Glinda, of course. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It gave her a great excuse to wear a sparkly dress and carry a wand. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But you watch that movie enough times, and you start to realize how unusual it is. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Now we live today, and are raising our children, in a kind of children's-fantasy-spectacular-industrial complex. </seg>
<seg id="8"> But "The Wizard of Oz" stood alone. </seg>
<seg id="9"> It did not start that trend. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Forty years later was when the trend really caught on, with, interestingly, another movie that featured a metal guy and a furry guy rescuing a girl by dressing up as the enemy's guards. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Do you know what I'm talking about? </seg>
<seg id="12"> Yeah. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Now, there's a big difference between these two movies, a couple of really big differences between "The Wizard of Oz" and all the movies we watch today. </seg>
<seg id="14"> One is there's very little violence in "The Wizard of Oz." </seg>
<seg id="15"> The monkeys are rather aggressive, as are the apple trees. </seg>
<seg id="16"> But I think if "The Wizard of Oz" were made today, the wizard would say, "Dorothy, you are the savior of Oz that the prophecy foretold. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Use your magic slippers to defeat the computer-generated armies of the Wicked Witch." </seg>
<seg id="18"> But that's not how it happens. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Another thing that's really unique about "The Wizard of Oz" to me is that all of the most heroic and wise and even villainous characters are female. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Now I started to notice this when I actually showed "Star Wars" to my daughter, which was years later, and the situation was different. </seg>
<seg id="21"> At that point I also had a son. </seg>
<seg id="22"> He was only three at the time. </seg>
<seg id="23"> He was not invited to the screening. He was too young for that. </seg>
<seg id="24"> But he was the second child, and the level of supervision had plummeted. </seg>
<seg id="25"> So he wandered in, and it imprinted on him like a mommy duck does to its duckling, and I don't think he understands what's going on, but he is sure soaking in it. </seg>
<seg id="26"> And I wonder what he's soaking in. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Is he picking up on the themes of courage and perseverance and loyalty? </seg>
<seg id="28"> Is he picking up on the fact that Luke joins an army to overthrow the government? </seg>
<seg id="29"> Is he picking up on the fact that there are only boys in the universe except for Aunt Beru, and of course this princess, who's really cool, but who kind of waits around through most of the movie so that she can award the hero with a medal and a wink to thank him for saving the universe, which he does by the magic that he was born with? </seg>
<seg id="30"> Compare this to 1939 with "The Wizard of Oz." </seg>
<seg id="31"> How does Dorothy win her movie? </seg>
<seg id="32"> By making friends with everybody and being a leader. </seg>
<seg id="33"> That's kind of the world I'd rather raise my kids in -- Oz, right? -- and not the world of dudes fighting, which is where we kind of have to be. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Why is there so much Force -- capital F, Force -- in the movies we have for our kids, and so little yellow brick road? </seg>
<seg id="35"> There is a lot of great writing about the impact that the boy-violent movie has on girls, and you should do that reading. It's very good. </seg>
<seg id="36"> I haven't read as much on how boys are picking up on this vibe. </seg>
<seg id="37"> I know from my own experience that Princess Leia did not provide the adequate context that I could have used in navigating the adult world that is co-ed. </seg>
<seg id="38"> I think there was a first-kiss moment when I really expected the credits to start rolling because that's the end of the movie, right? </seg>
<seg id="39"> I finished my quest, I got the girl. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Why are you still standing there? </seg>
<seg id="41"> I don't know what I'm supposed to do. </seg>
<seg id="42"> The movies are very, very focused on defeating the villain and getting your reward, and there's not a lot of room for other relationships and other journeys. </seg>
<seg id="43"> It's almost as though if you're a boy, you are a dopey animal, and if you are a girl, you should bring your warrior costume. </seg>
<seg id="44"> There are plenty of exceptions, and I will defend the Disney princesses in front of any you. </seg>
<seg id="45"> But they do send a message to boys, that they are not, the boys are not really the target audience. </seg>
<seg id="46"> They are doing a phenomenal job of teaching girls how to defend against the patriarchy, but they are not necessarily showing boys how they're supposed to defend against the patriarchy. </seg>
<seg id="47"> There's no models for them. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And we also have some terrific women who are writing new stories for our kids, and as three-dimensional and delightful as Hermione and Katniss are, these are still war movies. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And, of course, the most successful studio of all time continues to crank out classic after classic, every single one of them about the journey of a boy, or a man, or two men who are friends, or a man and his son, or two men who are raising a little girl. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Until, as many of you are thinking, this year, when they finally came out with "Brave." </seg>
<seg id="51"> I recommend it to all of you. It's on demand now. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Do you remember what the critics said when "Brave" came out? </seg>
<seg id="53"> "Aw, I can't believe Pixar made a princess movie." </seg>
<seg id="54"> It's very good. Don't let that stop you. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Now, almost none of these movies pass the Bechdel Test. </seg>
<seg id="56"> I don't know if you've heard of this. </seg>
<seg id="57"> It has not yet caught on and caught fire, but maybe today we will start a movement. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Alison Bechdel is a comic book artist, and back in the mid-'80s, she recorded this conversation she'd had with a friend about assessing the movies that they saw. </seg>
<seg id="59"> And it's very simple. There's just three questions you should ask: Is there more than one character in the movie that is female who has lines? </seg>
<seg id="60"> So try to meet that bar. </seg>
<seg id="61"> And do these women talk to each other at any point in the movie? </seg>
<seg id="62"> And is their conversation about something other than the guy that they both like? </seg>
<seg id="63"> Right? Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Thank you very much. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Two women who exist and talk to each other about stuff. </seg>
<seg id="66"> It does happen. I've seen it, and yet I very rarely see it in the movies that we know and love. </seg>
<seg id="67"> In fact, this week I went to see a very high-quality movie, "Argo." </seg>
<seg id="68"> Right? Oscar buzz, doing great at the box office, a consensus idea of what a quality Hollywood film is. </seg>
<seg id="69"> It pretty much flunks the Bechdel test. </seg>
<seg id="70"> And I don't think it should, because a lot of the movie, I don't know if you've seen it, but a lot of the movie takes place in this embassy where men and women are hiding out during the hostage crisis. </seg>
<seg id="71"> We've got quite a few scenes of the men having deep, angst-ridden conversations in this hideout, and the great moment for one of the actresses is to peek through the door and say, "Are you coming to bed, honey?" </seg>
<seg id="72"> That's Hollywood for you. </seg>
<seg id="73"> So let's look at the numbers. </seg>
<seg id="74"> 2011, of the 100 most popular movies, how many of them do you think actually have female protagonists? </seg>
<seg id="75"> Eleven. It's not bad. </seg>
<seg id="76"> It's not as many percent as the number of women we've just elected to Congress, so that's good. </seg>
<seg id="77"> But there is a number that is greater than this that's going to bring this room down. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Last year, The New York Times published a study that the government had done. </seg>
<seg id="79"> Here's what it said. </seg>
<seg id="80"> One out of five women in America say that they have been sexually assaulted some time in their life. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Now, I don't think that's the fault of popular entertainment. </seg>
<seg id="82"> I don't think kids' movies have anything to do with that. </seg>
<seg id="83"> I don't even think that music videos or pornography are really directly related to that, but something is going wrong, and when I hear that statistic, one of the things I think of is that's a lot of sexual assailants. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Who are these guys? What are they learning? </seg>
<seg id="85"> What are they failing to learn? </seg>
<seg id="86"> Are they absorbing the story that a male hero's job is to defeat the villain with violence and then collect the reward, which is a woman who has no friends and doesn't speak? </seg>
<seg id="87"> Are we soaking up that story? </seg>
<seg id="88"> You know, as a parent with the privilege of raising a daughter like all of you who are doing the same thing, we find this world and this statistic very alarming and we want to prepare them. </seg>
<seg id="89"> We have tools at our disposal like "girl power," and we hope that that will help, but I gotta wonder, is girl power going to protect them if, at the same time, actively or passively, we are training our sons to maintain their boy power? </seg>
<seg id="90"> I mean, I think the Netflix queue is one way that we can do something very important, and I'm talking mainly to the dads here. </seg>
<seg id="91"> I think we have got to show our sons a new definition of manhood. </seg>
<seg id="92"> The definition of manhood is already turning upside down. </seg>
<seg id="93"> You've read about how the new economy is changing the roles of caregiver and wage earner. </seg>
<seg id="94"> They're throwing it up in the air. </seg>
<seg id="95"> So our sons are going to have to find some way of adapting to this, some new relationship with each other, and I think we really have to show them, and model for them, how a real man is someone who trusts his sisters and respects them, and wants to be on their team, and stands up against the real bad guys, who are the men who want to abuse the women. </seg>
<seg id="96"> And I think our job in the Netflix queue is to look out for those movies that pass the Bechdel Test, if we can find them, and to seek out the heroines who are there, who show real courage, who bring people together, and to nudge our sons to identify with those heroines and to say, "I want to be on their team," because they're going to be on their team. </seg>
<seg id="97"> When I asked my daughter who her favorite character was in "Star Wars," do you know what she said? </seg>
<seg id="98"> Obi-Wan. </seg>
<seg id="99"> Obi-Wan Kenobi and Glinda. </seg>
<seg id="100"> What do these two have in common? </seg>
<seg id="101"> Maybe it's not just the sparkly dress. </seg>
<seg id="102"> I think these people are experts. </seg>
<seg id="103"> I think these are the two people in the movie who know more than anybody else, and they love sharing their knowledge with other people to help them reach their potential. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Now, they are leaders. </seg>
<seg id="105"> I like that kind of quest for my daughter, and I like that kind of quest for my son. </seg>
<seg id="106"> I want more quests like that. </seg>
<seg id="107"> I want fewer quests where my son is told, "Go out and fight it alone," and more quests where he sees that it's his job to join a team, maybe a team led by women, to help other people become better and be better people, like the Wizard of Oz. </seg>
<seg id="108"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1864" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/mohamed_ali_the_link_between_unemployment_and_terrorism.html</url>
<description>For the young and unemployed in the world's big cities, dreams of opportunity and wealth do come true -- but too often because they're heavily recruited by terrorist groups and other violent organizations. Human rights advocate Mohamed Ali draws on stories from his native Mogadishu to make a powerful case for innovation incubators for our cities' young and ambitious.</description>
<keywords>Africa,business,entrepreneur,global issues,innovation,peace,violence,youth</keywords>
<talkid>1864</talkid>
<title>Mohamed Ali: The link between unemployment and terrorism</title>
<seg id="1"> I would like to talk to you about a story about a small town kid. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I don't know his name, but I do know his story. </seg>
<seg id="3"> He lives in a small village in southern Somalia. </seg>
<seg id="4"> His village is near Mogadishu. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Drought drives the small village into poverty and to the brink of starvation. </seg>
<seg id="6"> With nothing left for him there, he leaves for the big city, in this case, Mogadishu, the capital of Somalia. </seg>
<seg id="7"> When he arrives, there are no opportunities, no jobs, no way forward. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He ends up living in a tent city on the outskirts of Mogadishu. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Maybe a year passes, nothing. </seg>
<seg id="10"> One day, he's approached by a gentleman who offers to take him to lunch, then to dinner, to breakfast. </seg>
<seg id="11"> He meets this dynamic group of people, and they give him a break. </seg>
<seg id="12"> He's given a bit of money to buy himself some new clothes, money to send back home to his family. </seg>
<seg id="13"> He is introduced to this young woman. </seg>
<seg id="14"> He eventually gets married. </seg>
<seg id="15"> He starts this new life. </seg>
<seg id="16"> He has a purpose in life. </seg>
<seg id="17"> One beautiful day in Mogadishu, under an azure blue sky, a car bomb goes off. </seg>
<seg id="18"> That small town kid with the big city dreams was the suicide bomber, and that dynamic group of people were al Shabaab, a terrorist organization linked to al Qaeda. </seg>
<seg id="19"> So how does the story of a small town kid just trying to make it big in the city end up with him blowing himself up? </seg>
<seg id="20"> He was waiting. </seg>
<seg id="21"> He was waiting for an opportunity, waiting to begin his future, waiting for a way forward, and this was the first thing that came along. </seg>
<seg id="22"> This was the first thing that pulled him out of what we call waithood. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And his story repeats itself in urban centers around the world. </seg>
<seg id="24"> It is the story of the disenfranchised, unemployed urban youth who sparks riots in Johannesburg, sparks riots in London, who reaches out for something other than waithood. </seg>
<seg id="25"> For young people, the promise of the city, the big city dream is that of opportunity, of jobs, of wealth, but young people are not sharing in the prosperity of their cities. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Often it's youth who suffer from the highest unemployment rates. </seg>
<seg id="27"> By 2030, three out of five people living in cities will be under the age of 18. </seg>
<seg id="28"> If we do not include young people in the growth of our cities, if we do not provide them opportunities, the story of waithood, the gateway to terrorism, to violence, to gangs, will be the story of cities 2.0. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And in my city of birth, Mogadishu, 70 percent of young people suffer from unemployment. </seg>
<seg id="30"> 70 percent don't work, don't go to school. </seg>
<seg id="31"> They pretty much do nothing. </seg>
<seg id="32"> I went back to Mogadishu last month, and I went to visit Madina Hospital, the hospital I was born in. </seg>
<seg id="33"> I remember standing in front of that bullet-ridden hospital thinking, what if I had never left? </seg>
<seg id="34"> What if I had been forced into that same state of waithood? </seg>
<seg id="35"> Would I have become a terrorist? </seg>
<seg id="36"> I'm not really sure about the answer. </seg>
<seg id="37"> My reason for being in Mogadishu that month was actually to host a youth leadership and entrepreneurship summit. </seg>
<seg id="38"> I brought together about 90 young Somali leaders. </seg>
<seg id="39"> We sat down and brainstormed on solutions to the biggest challenges facing their city. </seg>
<seg id="40"> One of the young men in the room was Aden. </seg>
<seg id="41"> He went to university in Mogadishu, graduated. </seg>
<seg id="42"> There were no jobs, no opportunities. </seg>
<seg id="43"> I remember him telling me, because he was a college graduate, unemployed, frustrated, that he was the perfect target for al Shabaab and other terrorist organizations, to be recruited. </seg>
<seg id="44"> They sought people like him out. </seg>
<seg id="45"> But his story takes a different route. </seg>
<seg id="46"> In Mogadishu, the biggest barrier to getting from point A to point B are the roads. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Twenty-three years of civil war have completely destroyed the road system, and a motorbike can be the easiest way to get around. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Aden saw an opportunity and seized it. </seg>
<seg id="49"> He started a motorbike company. </seg>
<seg id="50"> He began renting out motorbikes to local residents who couldn't normally afford them. </seg>
<seg id="51"> He bought 10 bikes, with the help of family and friends, and his dream is to eventually expand to several hundred within the next three years. </seg>
<seg id="52"> How is this story different? </seg>
<seg id="53"> What makes his story different? </seg>
<seg id="54"> I believe it is his ability to identify and seize a new opportunity. </seg>
<seg id="55"> It's entrepreneurship, and I believe entrepreneurship can be the most powerful tool against waithood. </seg>
<seg id="56"> It empowers young people to be the creators of the very economic opportunities they are so desperately seeking. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And you can train young people to be entrepreneurs. </seg>
<seg id="58"> I want to talk to you about a young man who attended one of my meetings, Mohamed Mohamoud, a florist. </seg>
<seg id="59"> He was helping me train some of the young people at the summit in entrepreneurship and how to be innovative and how to create a culture of entrepreneurship. </seg>
<seg id="60"> He's actually the first florist Mogadishu has seen in over 22 years, and until recently, until Mohamed came along, if you wanted flowers at your wedding, you used plastic bouquets shipped from abroad. </seg>
<seg id="61"> If you asked someone, "When was the last time you saw fresh flowers?" for many who grew up under civil war, the answer would be, "Never." </seg>
<seg id="62"> So Mohamed saw an opportunity. </seg>
<seg id="63"> He started a landscaping and design floral company. </seg>
<seg id="64"> He created a farm right outside of Mogadishu, and started growing tulips and lilies, which he said could survive the harsh Mogadishu climate. </seg>
<seg id="65"> And he began delivering flowers to weddings, creating gardens at homes and businesses around the city, and he's now working on creating Mogadishu's first public park in 22 years. </seg>
<seg id="66"> There's no public park in Mogadishu. </seg>
<seg id="67"> He wants to create a space where families, young people, can come together, and, as he says, smell the proverbial roses. </seg>
<seg id="68"> And he doesn't grow roses because they use too much water, by the way. </seg>
<seg id="69"> So the first step is to inspire young people, and in that room, Mohamed's presence had a really profound impact on the youth in that room. </seg>
<seg id="70"> They had never really thought about starting up a business. </seg>
<seg id="71"> They've thought about working for an NGO, working for the government, but his story, his innovation, really had a strong impact on them. </seg>
<seg id="72"> He forced them to look at their city as a place of opportunity. </seg>
<seg id="73"> He empowered them to believe that they could be entrepreneurs, that they could be change makers. </seg>
<seg id="74"> By the end of the day, they were coming up with innovative solutions to some of the biggest challenges facing their city. </seg>
<seg id="75"> They came up with entrepreneurial solutions to local problems. </seg>
<seg id="76"> So inspiring young people and creating a culture of entrepreneurship is a really great step, but young people need capital to make their ideas a reality. </seg>
<seg id="77"> They need expertise and mentorship to guide them in developing and launching their businesses. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Connect young people with the resources they need, provide them the support they need to go from ideation to creation, and you will create catalysts for urban growth. </seg>
<seg id="79"> For me, entrepreneurship is more than just starting up a business. </seg>
<seg id="80"> It's about creating a social impact. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Mohamed is not simply selling flowers. </seg>
<seg id="82"> I believe he is selling hope. </seg>
<seg id="83"> His Peace Park, and that's what he calls it, when it's created, will actually transform the way people see their city. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Aden hired street kids to help rent out and maintain those bikes for him. </seg>
<seg id="85"> He gave them the opportunity to escape the paralysis of waithood. </seg>
<seg id="86"> These young entrepreneurs are having a tremendous impact in their cities. </seg>
<seg id="87"> So my suggestion is, turn youth into entrepreneurs, incubate and nurture their inherent innovation, and you will have more stories of flowers and Peace Parks than of car bombs and waithood. </seg>
<seg id="88"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1477" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/sarah_parcak_archeology_from_space.html</url>
<description>In this short talk, Fellow Sarah Parcak introduces the field of "space archeology" -- using satellite images to search for clues to the lost sites of past civilizations.</description>
<keywords>TED Fellows,exploration,history,science,space,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1477</talkid>
<title>Sarah Parcak: Archeology from space</title>
<seg id="1"> When I was a child growing up in Maine, one of my favorite things to do was to look for sand dollars on the seashores of Maine, because my parents told me it would bring me luck. </seg>
<seg id="2"> But you know, these shells, they're hard to find. </seg>
<seg id="3"> They're covered in sand. They're difficult to see. </seg>
<seg id="4"> However, overtime, I got used to looking for them. </seg>
<seg id="5"> I started seeing shapes and patterns that helped me to collect them. </seg>
<seg id="6"> This grew into a passion for finding things, a love for the past and archaeology. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And eventually when I started studying Egyptology, I realized that seeing with my naked eyes alone wasn't enough. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Because all of the sudden in Egypt my beach had grown from a tiny beach in Maine to one eight hundred miles long next to the Nile, and my sand dollars had grown to the size of cities. </seg>
<seg id="9"> This is really what brought me to using satellite imagery. </seg>
<seg id="10"> For trying to map the past, I knew that I had to see differently. </seg>
<seg id="11"> So I want to show you an example of how we see differently using the infrared. </seg>
<seg id="12"> This is a site located in the eastern Egyptian delta called Bendix. </seg>
<seg id="13"> And the site visibly appears brown, but when we use the infrared and we process it, all of the sudden, using false color, the site appears as bright pink. </seg>
<seg id="14"> What you are seeing are the actual chemical changes to the landscape caused by the building materials and activities of the ancient Egyptians. </seg>
<seg id="15"> What I want to share with you today is how we've used satellite data to find an ancient Egyptian city, called Itjtawy, missing for thousands of years. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Itjtawy was ancient Egypt's capital for over four hundred years, at a period of time called the Middle Kingdom about four thousand years ago. </seg>
<seg id="17"> The site is located in the Faiyum of Egypt and site is really important because in the Middle Kingdom there was this great renaissance for ancient Egyptian art, architecture and religion. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Egyptologists have always known the site of Itjtawy was located somewhere near the pyramids of the two kings who built it, indicated within the red circles here, but somewhere within this massive flood plane. </seg>
<seg id="19"> This area is huge -- it's four miles by three miles in size. </seg>
<seg id="20"> The Nile used to flow right next to the city of Itjtawy, and as it shifted and changed and moved over time to the east, it covered over the city. </seg>
<seg id="21"> So, how do you find a buried city in a vast landscape? </seg>
<seg id="22"> Finding it randomly would be the equivalent of locating a needle in a haystack, blindfolded wearing baseball mitts. </seg>
<seg id="23"> So what we did is we used NASA topography data to map out the landscape, very subtle changes. </seg>
<seg id="24"> We started to be able to see where the Nile used to flow. </seg>
<seg id="25"> But you can see in more detail -- and even more interesting -- this very slight raised area seen within the circle up here, which we thought could possibly be the location of the city of Itjtawy. </seg>
<seg id="26"> So we collaborated with the Egyptian scientists to do coring work, which you see here. </seg>
<seg id="27"> When I say coring, it's like ice coring, but instead of layers of climate change you're looking for layers of human occupation. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And five meters down, underneath a thick layer of mud, we found a dense layer of pottery. </seg>
<seg id="29"> What this shows is that at this possible location of Itjtawy, five meters down, we have of layer of occupation for several hundred years dating to the Middle Kingdom, dating to the exact period of time we think Itjtawy is. </seg>
<seg id="30"> We also found work stone -- carnelian, quartz and agate that shows that there was a jewelers workshop here. </seg>
<seg id="31"> These might not look like much, but when you think about the most common stones used in jewelry from the Middle Kingdom, these are the stones that were used. </seg>
<seg id="32"> So, we have a dense layer of occupation dating to the Middle Kingdom at this site. </seg>
<seg id="33"> We also have evidence of an elite jewelers workshop, showing that whatever was there was a very important city. </seg>
<seg id="34"> No Itjtawy was here yet, but we're going to be returning to the site in the near future to map it out. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And even more importantly, we have funding to train young Egyptians in the use of satellite technology so they can be the ones making great discoveries as well. </seg>
<seg id="36"> So I wanted to end with my favorite quote from the Middle Kingdom -- it was probably written at the city of Itjtawy four thousand years ago. </seg>
<seg id="37"> "Sharing knowledge is the greatest of all callings. </seg>
<seg id="38"> There's nothing like it in the land." </seg>
<seg id="39"> So as it turns out, TED was not founded in 1984 AD. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Making ideas actually started in 1984 BC at a not-lost-for-long city, found from above. </seg>
<seg id="41"> It certainly puts finding seashells by the seashore in perspective. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Thank you very much. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1736" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/shaolan_learn_to_read_chinese_with_ease.html</url>
<description>For foreigners, learning to speak Chinese is a hard task. But learning to read the beautiful, often complex characters of the Chinese written language may be less difficult. ShaoLan walks through a simple lesson in recognizing the ideas behind the characters and their meaning -- building from a few simple forms to more complex concepts. Call it Chineasy.</description>
<keywords>china,education,language</keywords>
<talkid>1736</talkid>
<title>ShaoLan: Learn to read Chinese ... with ease!</title>
<seg id="1"> Growing up in Taiwan as the daughter of a calligrapher, one of my most treasured memories was my mother showing me the beauty, the shape and the form of Chinese characters. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Ever since then, I was fascinated by this incredible language. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But to an outsider, it seems to be as impenetrable as the Great Wall of China. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Over the past few years, I've been wondering if I can break down this wall, so anyone who wants to understand and appreciate the beauty of this sophisticated language could do so. </seg>
<seg id="5"> I started thinking about how a new, fast method of learning Chinese might be useful. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Since the age of five, I started to learn how to draw every single stroke for each character in the correct sequence. </seg>
<seg id="7"> I learned new characters every day during the course of the next 15 years. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Since we only have five minutes, it's better that we have a fast and simpler way. </seg>
<seg id="9"> A Chinese scholar would understand 20,000 characters. </seg>
<seg id="10"> You only need 1,000 to understand the basic literacy. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The top 200 will allow you to comprehend 40 percent of basic literature -- enough to read road signs, restaurant menus, to understand the basic idea of the web pages or the newspapers. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Today I'm going to start with eight to show you how the method works. </seg>
<seg id="13"> You are ready? </seg>
<seg id="14"> Open your mouth as wide as possible until it's square. </seg>
<seg id="15"> You get a mouth. </seg>
<seg id="16"> This is a person going for a walk. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Person. </seg>
<seg id="18"> If the shape of the fire is a person with two arms on both sides, as if she was yelling frantically, "Help! I'm on fire!" -- This symbol actually is originally from the shape of the flame, but I like to think that way. Whichever works for you. </seg>
<seg id="19"> This is a tree. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Tree. </seg>
<seg id="21"> This is a mountain. </seg>
<seg id="22"> The sun. </seg>
<seg id="23"> The moon. </seg>
<seg id="24"> The symbol of the door looks like a pair of saloon doors in the wild west. </seg>
<seg id="25"> I call these eight characters radicals. </seg>
<seg id="26"> They are the building blocks for you to create lots more characters. </seg>
<seg id="27"> A person. </seg>
<seg id="28"> If someone walks behind, that is "to follow." </seg>
<seg id="29"> As the old saying goes, two is company, three is a crowd. </seg>
<seg id="30"> If a person stretched their arms wide, this person is saying, "It was this big." </seg>
<seg id="31"> The person inside the mouth, the person is trapped. </seg>
<seg id="32"> He's a prisoner, just like Jonah inside the whale. </seg>
<seg id="33"> One tree is a tree. Two trees together, we have the woods. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Three trees together, we create the forest. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Put a plank underneath the tree, we have the foundation. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Put a mouth on the top of the tree, that's "idiot." </seg>
<seg id="37"> Easy to remember, since a talking tree is pretty idiotic. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Remember fire? </seg>
<seg id="39"> Two fires together, I get really hot. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Three fires together, that's a lot of flames. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Set the fire underneath the two trees, it's burning. </seg>
<seg id="42"> For us, the sun is the source of prosperity. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Two suns together, prosperous. </seg>
<seg id="44"> Three together, that's sparkles. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Put the sun and the moon shining together, it's brightness. </seg>
<seg id="46"> It also means tomorrow, after a day and a night. </seg>
<seg id="47"> The sun is coming up above the horizon. Sunrise. </seg>
<seg id="48"> A door. Put a plank inside the door, it's a door bolt. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Put a mouth inside the door, asking questions. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Knock knock. Is anyone home? </seg>
<seg id="51"> This person is sneaking out of a door, escaping, evading. </seg>
<seg id="52"> On the left, we have a woman. </seg>
<seg id="53"> Two women together, they have an argument. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Three women together, be careful, it's adultery. </seg>
<seg id="55"> So we have gone through almost 30 characters. </seg>
<seg id="56"> By using this method, the first eight radicals will allow you to build 32. </seg>
<seg id="57"> The next group of eight characters will build an extra 32. </seg>
<seg id="58"> So with very little effort, you will be able to learn a couple hundred characters, which is the same as a Chinese eight-year-old. </seg>
<seg id="59"> So after we know the characters, we start building phrases. </seg>
<seg id="60"> For example, the mountain and the fire together, we have fire mountain. It's a volcano. </seg>
<seg id="61"> We know Japan is the land of the rising sun. </seg>
<seg id="62"> This is a sun placed with the origin, because Japan lies to the east of China. </seg>
<seg id="63"> So a sun, origin together, we build Japan. </seg>
<seg id="64"> A person behind Japan, what do we get? </seg>
<seg id="65"> A Japanese person. </seg>
<seg id="66"> The character on the left is two mountains stacked on top of each other. </seg>
<seg id="67"> In ancient China, that means in exile, because Chinese emperors, they put their political enemies in exile beyond mountains. </seg>
<seg id="68"> Nowadays, exile has turned into getting out. </seg>
<seg id="69"> A mouth which tells you where to get out is an exit. </seg>
<seg id="70"> This is a slide to remind me that I should stop talking and get off of the stage. Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
</srcset>
</mteval>
